<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="citation">
   <head>
      <gi>citation</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="en">Citation</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="en">A linking element that cites an external resource.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description">
      <p xml:lang="en">
         <gi>citation</gi> is a generic linking element that cites an external resource in machine
								and / or human readable form, which is available within a number of descriptive elements.
								The purpose of the <gi>citation</gi> element is to point to a resource that provides
								descriptive data which is not otherwise given in the EAC-CPF instance, such as an original
								document that sets out the mandate for a corporate body; it should not be confused with the
									<gi>source</gi> element which is used to declare a particular resource used in the
								composition of the EAC-CPF instance. In most contexts it is optional, but a
									<gi>citation</gi> element must be given within <gi>conventionDeclaration</gi> and
									<gi>localTypeDeclaration</gi> elements in <gi>control</gi>. Provide the formal title or
								name of the resource, using the <gi>span</gi> element to indicate any formatting (such as
								italic or bold etc) thought necessary. The user experience can be controlled by use of the
								available XML linking Language (Xlink) attributes for which consult the specification at
								http://www.w3.org/TR/xlink/.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>[text], span</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>biogHist, conventionDeclaration, function, legalStatus, localDescription,
							localTypeDeclaration, mandate, occupation, place</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="en">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>lastDateTimeVerified</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xlink:actuate</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xlink:arcrole</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xlink:href</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xlink:role</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xlink:show</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xlink:title</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xlink:type</label>
            <item>Required (if any XLINK attributes used)</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>0...∞ or 1...∞</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML>
         <eac-cpf:conventionDeclaration xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:abbreviation>AFNOR</eac-cpf:abbreviation>
            <eac-cpf:citation>Indexation conforme à la norme AFNOR NF Z44-060 (decembre 1996)
										Documentation - Catalogue d'auteurs et d'anonymes-formes et structures des vedettes de
										collectivites - auteurs</eac-cpf:citation>
         </eac-cpf:conventionDeclaration>
         <eac-cpf:conventionDeclaration xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:abbreviation>USNARA-LDRG</eac-cpf:abbreviation>
            <eac-cpf:citation>U.S. National Archives and Records Administration, Lifecycle Data
										Requirements Guide (for creating the authorized form of the name).</eac-cpf:citation>
         </eac-cpf:conventionDeclaration>
         <eac-cpf:mandate xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:citation>FR ANOM COL C11D 1 Fo 179-179vo : concession de peche en Acadie par le
										Roi à Bergier, Gaultier, Boucher et autres date du 3 mars 1684.</eac-cpf:citation>
         </eac-cpf:mandate>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>