<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="biogHist">
   <head>
      <gi>biogHist</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="en">Biographical or Historical Note</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="en">A concise essay and/or chronology that provides biographical or historical
							information about the EAC-CPF entity.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description">
      <p xml:lang="en">The <gi>biogHist</gi> includes significant details about the life of an individual or
								family, or the administrative history of a corporate body. The <gi>biogHist</gi> may
								contain just text in a series of Paragraphs <gi>p</gi>, and/or a Chronology List
									<gi>chronList</gi> that matches dates and date ranges with associated events and/or
								places. The <gi>abstract</gi> element is intended to provide a very brief synopsis of the
								full <gi>biogHist</gi> content that could be extracted for inclusion in a remote source,
								such as a MARC record.</p>
      <p xml:lang="en">The optional <gi>citation</gi>, <gi>list</gi>, and <gi>outline</gi> elements are
								used to accommodate greater complexity in expressing or representing the biography or
								history being described. A simpler discursive expression of the information may be encoded
								as one or more <gi>p</gi> elements.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>abstract, chronList, citation, list, outline, p</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>description</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="en">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p> ISAAR 5.2.2</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>0...∞</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML>
         <eac-cpf:biogHist xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:abstract>Established in 1961, the United States Peace Corps administered and
										coordinated Federal international volunteer and related domestic volunteer programs in
										areas of agricultural assistance, community development, education, environmental
										protection, and nation assistance.</eac-cpf:abstract>
            <eac-cpf:p>The Peace Corps was established as an operating agency in the Department of
										State Delegation of Authority 85-11, effective March 3, 1961, pursuant to Executive Order
										(E.O.) 10924, March 1, 1961. It was recognized legislatively by the Peace Corps Act (75
										Stat. 612), approved September 22, 1961. The Peace Corps was reassigned to the newly
										established ACTION by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1971, effective July 1, 1971. It was
										made autonomous within ACTION by E.O. 12137, May 16, 1979, and was made an independent
										agency by Title VI of the International Security and Development Corporation Act of 1981
										(95 Stat. 1540), February 21, 1982. The Peace Corps administered and coordinated Federal
										international volunteer and related domestic volunteer programs including the areas of
										agricultural assistance, community development, education, environmental protection, and
										nation assistance.</eac-cpf:p>
         </eac-cpf:biogHist>
         <eac-cpf:biogHist xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:p>Ilma Mary Brewer, nee Pidgeon, was Lecturer in Botany/Biology, University of
										Sydney 1963-70 and Senior Lecturer in Biological Sciences 1970-78. She developed new
										methods of teaching based on the recognition that a student learnt more by working at
										his/her own place and instruction him/her self. Her findings were published as a book,
										"Learning More and Teaching Less."</eac-cpf:p>
            <eac-cpf:chronList>
               <eac-cpf:chronItem>
                  <eac-cpf:date standardDate="1936">1936</eac-cpf:date>
                  <eac-cpf:event>Bachelor of Science (BSc) completed at the University of
												Sydney</eac-cpf:event>
               </eac-cpf:chronItem>
               <eac-cpf:chronItem>
                  <eac-cpf:date standardDate="1937">1937</eac-cpf:date>
                  <eac-cpf:event>Master of Science (MSc) completed at the University of
												Sydney</eac-cpf:event>
               </eac-cpf:chronItem>
               <eac-cpf:chronItem>
                  <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                     <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1937">1937</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                     <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1941">1941</eac-cpf:toDate>
                  </eac-cpf:dateRange>
                  <eac-cpf:event>Linnean Macleay Fellow</eac-cpf:event>
               </eac-cpf:chronItem>
            </eac-cpf:chronList>
         </eac-cpf:biogHist>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>