<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="date">
   <head>
      <gi>date</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="en">Date</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="en">The single date of an event in the history of, or a relationship with, the
							person, family, or corporate body being described in the EAC-CPF instance.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description">
      <p xml:lang="en">A generic element expressing the single date of an event in the history of, or a
								relationship with, the person, family, or corporate body being described in the EAC-CPF
								instance. If the event or relationship has inclusive dates use the <gi>dateRange</gi>
								element, while more complex dates (combining singles dates and date ranges) can be expressed
								in <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
      <p xml:lang="en">The content of the element is intended to be a human-readable natural language date with a
								machine-readable date provided as the value of the <att>standardDate</att> attribute,
								formulated according to ISO 8601. Other attributes include <att>notBefore</att> and
									<att>notAfter</att> for dates of uncertainty. The <att>localType</att> attribute can be
								used to supply a more specific characterization of the date.</p>
      <p xml:lang="en">Dates of existence for the entity being described in the EAC-CPF instance are encoded with
								the <gi>existDates</gi> element, while the dates of use of a particular name of an entity
								are encoded in <gi>useDates</gi>. The date and time of a maintenance event in the history
								of the EAC-CPF instance are given in the <gi>eventDateTime</gi> element.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>[text]</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>chronItem, cpfRelation, dateSet, existDates, function, functionRelation,
							legalStatus, localControl, localDescription, mandate, occupation, place, resourceRelation,
							useDates</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="en">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>notAfter</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>notBefore</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>standardDate</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>0...∞</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML>
         <eac-cpf:date xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" standardDate="1765-09-18">September 18, 1765</eac-cpf:date>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>