<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="generalContext" type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>generalContext</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="ger">Allgemeiner Kontext</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="ger"
         >Beschreibung des allgemeinen sozialen und kulturellen Kontextes einer Entität</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description">
      <p xml:lang="ger"
            >Das Element <gi>generalContext</gi> kann mit den Subelementen <gi>list</gi>, <gi>outline</gi> oder <gi>p</gi> Informationen zum sozialen, kulturellen, wirtschaftlichen, politischen und/oder historischen Umfeld einer Entität beschreiben. Im <gi>generalContext</gi>-Element werden alle Informationen zu einer Entität erfasst, die nicht in einem der anderen Elemente in <gi>description</gi> eingetragen werden.</p>
      <p xml:lang="ger"
            >Die optionalen Elemente <gi>citation</gi>, <gi>list</gi> und <gi>outline</gi> können genutzt werden, um komplexe Strukturen im allgemeinen Kontext abbilden zu können. Beschreibender Text kann in einem oder mehreren <gi>p</gi>-Elementen erfasst werden.</p>
   </div>

   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>citation, list, outline, p</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>description</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>

   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.2.8</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <div type="mandatory">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Optional</p>
      </div>
      <div type="repeatable">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Repeatable</p>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <_0:egXML xmlns:_0="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng">
         <eac-cpf:generalContext xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:p>Edward Koiko Mabo was born in 1936 on the island of Mer, one of the Murray
										Islands, which are located at the eastern extremity of Torres Strait. In June 1992, six
										months after his death, Mabo achieved national prominence as the successful principal
										plaintiff in the landmark High Court ruling on native land title. The High Court ruling,
										for the first time, gave legal recognition to the fact that indigenous land ownership
										existed in Australia before European settlement and that, in some cases, this land tenure
										was not subsequently extinguished by the Crown.</eac-cpf:p>
         </eac-cpf:generalContext>
      </_0:egXML>
   </div>
</div>
