<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="structureOrGenealogy" type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="ger">Verwaltungsstruktur oder Stammbaum</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="ger"
         >Eine Beschreibung der internen Verwaltungsstruktur einer Körperschaft oder des Stammbaums einer Familie.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description">
      <p xml:lang="ger"
         >Das Element <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi> im beschreibenden Teil des EAC-CPF-Dokuments enthält Informationen über die internen Strukturen einer Körperschaft und Zeitangaben über Veränderungen dieser Strukturen, die für das Verständnis der Geschichte der Körperschaft notwendig sind. Das Element kann auch den Stammbaum einer Familie enthalten, in dem die Wechselbeziehungen zwischen einzelnen Familienmitgliedern und Datierungen abgebildet sind.</p>
      <p xml:lang="ger"
            >Die optionalen Elemente <gi>list</gi> und <gi>outline</gi> erlauben die Darstellung komplexer Strukturen. Im Element <gi>citation</gi> kann eine Verlinkung zu einem externen Dokument, wie einem Organigramm angegeben werden. Einfache textliche Beschreibungen werden in einem oder mehreren <gi>p</gi>-Elementen erfasst.</p>
      <p xml:lang="ger"
            >Alternativ können genealogische oder administrative Strukturen auch in beschreibender Form im Element <gi>biogHist</gi> (ISAAR (CPF) 5.2.2 History) und/oder mit dem <gi>cpfRelation</gi>-Element (ISAAR (CPF) 5.3) angegeben werden. Das Element <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi> sollte genutzt werden, wenn gegliederte Informationen über Strukturen kodiert werden.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>citation, list, outline, p</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>description</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="gloss">
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.2.7</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <div type="mandatory">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Optional</p>
      </div>
      <div type="repeatable">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Repeatable</p>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <_0:egXML xmlns:_0="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng">
         <eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:p>Sir Edward Noel (d 1643) married Julian, daughter and co-heir of Baptists Hicks (d 1629), Viscount Campden, and succeeded to the viscouty of Campden and a portion of his father-in-law's estates. The third Viscount Campden (1612-82) married Hester Wotton, daughter of the second Baron Wotton. The fourth Viscount Campden (1641-1689, created Earl of Gainsborough, 1682) married Elizabeth Wriothesley, elder daughter of the fourth Earl of Southampton. Jane Noel (d 1811), sister of the fifth and sixth Earls of Gainsborough, married Gerard Anne Edwards of Welham Grove (Leicetershire) and had issue Gerard Noel Edwards (1759-1838). He married in 1780 Diana Middleton (1762-1823 suo jure Baroness Barham), daughter of Charles Middleton (1726-1813), created first Baronet of Barham Court (Kent) in 1781 and first Baron Barham in 1805. GN Edwards assumed the surname Noel in 1798 on inheriting the sixth Earl of Gainborough's Rutland and Gloucestershire estates (though not the Earl's honours, which were extinguished); and he later inherited his father-in-law's baronetcy. His eldest son John Noel (1781-1866) succeeded to the estates of his mother and his father, to his mother's barony and his father's baronetcy, and was created Viscount Campden and Earl of Gainsborough in 1841.</eac-cpf:p>
         </eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy>
      </_0:egXML>
      <_0:egXML xmlns:_0="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng">
         <eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:p>The organogram of the<eac-cpf:span style="font-style:italic"
                  >Ministry of Culture and Tourism</eac-cpf:span>before its incorporation with the Ministry of Education and Religious Affairs, was the following:</eac-cpf:p>
            <eac-cpf:outline>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="first">
                  <eac-cpf:item>Minister of Culture and Tourism</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="second">
                  <eac-cpf:item>Deputy Minister of Culture and Tourism</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary of Tourism</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary of Sports</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary of Culture</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary for Culture and Tourism Infrastructure</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
            </eac-cpf:outline>
         </eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy>
      </_0:egXML>
   </div>
</div>
