<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="abstract" type="elementDocumentation">
    <head>
        <gi>abstract</gi>
    </head>
    <div type="fullName">
        <p xml:lang="ger">Auszug</p>
    </div>
    <div type="summary">
        <p xml:lang="ger">Zusammenfassung der Informationen, die im übergeordneten Element <gi>biogHist</gi> als Gesamtes vorhanden sind.</p>
    </div>
    <div type="description">
        <p xml:lang="ger">Das Element <gi>abstract</gi> dient als ein- bis zweizeilige Zusammenfassung der Biographie oder Entwicklungsgeschichte der beschriebenen Entität als Auszug aus der umfassenderen Beschreibung im übergeordneten Element <gi>biogHist</gi>. Mit den hier enthaltenen Informationen soll es dem Nutzer möglich sein, die beschriebene Entität schnell und eindeutig zu identifizieren. Der Inhalt des Elements <gi>abstract</gi> bietet sich zudem zum Harvesting durch andere Systeme als erläuternder Kontext für das Element <gi>nameEntry</gi> an, wenn dessen Inhalt beispielsweise als Suchresultat angezeigt wird.</p>
    </div>
    <div type="mayContain">
        <p>[text], span</p>
    </div>
    <div type="mayOccurWithin">
        <p>biogHist</p>
    </div>
    <div type="attributes">
        <p xml:lang="eng">
            <list type="gloss">
                <label>localType</label>
                <item>optional</item>
                <label>xml:id</label>
                <item>optional</item>
                <label>xml:lang</label>
                <item>optional</item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </div>
    <div type="occurrence">
        <div type="mandatory">
            <p xml:lang="eng">Optional</p>
        </div>
        <div type="repeatable">
            <p xml:lang="eng">Non-repeatable</p>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div type="examples">
        <egXML xml:lang="eng" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
            <eac-cpf:biogHist xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
                <eac-cpf:abstract>Hubert H. Humphrey was born in Wallace, South Dakota (1911). He  was elected Mayor of Minneapolis in 1945 and served until 1948.  In November of 1948, he was elected to the United
                    States Senate and he also served as the Senate Democratic Whip from 1961 to 1964 and in 1968, Humphrey was the Democratic
                    Party's candidate for President, but he was defeated by Richard M. Nixon. </eac-cpf:abstract>
                <eac-cpf:p>Hubert H. Humphrey was born in Wallace, South Dakota, on May 27,
                    1911. He left South Dakota to attend the University of Minnesota but
                    returned to South Dakota to help manage his fathers drug store early
                    in the depression. He attended the Capitol College of Pharmacy in
                    Denver, Colorado, and became a register pharmacist in 1933. On
                    September 3, 1936, Humphrey married Muriel Fay Buck. He returned
                    to the University of Minnesota and earned a B.A. degree in 1939. In
                    1940 he earned an M.A. in political science from Louisiana State
                    University and returned to Minneapolis to teach and pursue further
                    graduate study, he began working for the W.P.A. (Works Progress
                    Administration). He moved on from there to a series of positions with
                    wartime agencies. In 1943, he ran unsuccessfully for Mayor of
                    Minneapolis and returned to teaching as a visiting professor at
                    Macalester College in St. Paul. Between 1943 and 1945 Humphrey
                    worked at a variety of jobs. In 1945, he was elected Mayor of
                    Minneapolis and served until 1948. In 1948, at the Democratic
                    National Convention, he gained national attention when he delivered a
                    stirring speech in favor of a strong civil rights plank in the partys
                    platform. In November of 1948, Humphrey was elected to the United
                    States Senate. He served as the Senate Democratic Whip from 1961 to
                    1964.</eac-cpf:p>
                <eac-cpf:p>In 1964, at the Democratic National Convention, President Lyndon B.
                    Johnson asked the convention to select Humphrey as the Vice
                    Presidential nominee. The ticket was elected in November in a
                    Democratic landslide. In 1968, Humphrey was the Democratic
                    Partys candidate for President, but he was defeated narrowly by
                    Richard M. Nixon. After the defeat, Humphrey returned to Minnesota
                    to teach at the University of Minnesota and Macalester College. He
                    returned to the U.S. Senate in 1971, and he won re-election in 1976.
                    He died January 13, 1978 of cancer.</eac-cpf:p>
            </eac-cpf:biogHist>
        </egXML>
    </div>
</div>
