<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schemas/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xml:id="generalContext"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>generalContext</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">General Context</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">An element that encodes information about the general social and cultural
							context of the entity being described.</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>The element <gi>generalContext</gi> may contain a <gi>list</gi>, <gi>outline</gi>,
								or <gi>p</gi> element to format information about the social, cultural, economic,
								political, and/or historical milieu in which the entity being described existed. The general
								context provides wide latitude to record contextual information not specifically
								accommodated by other <gi>description</gi> elements.</p>
      <p>The optional <gi>citation</gi>, <gi>list</gi>, and <gi>outline</gi> elements are
								used to accommodate greater complexity in expressing or representing the general context
								being described. A simpler discursive expression of the general context may be encoded as
								one or more <gi>p</gi> elements.</p>
   </div>
   
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>citation, list, outline, p</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>description</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.2.8</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>0...∞</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:generalContext xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:p>Edward Koiko Mabo was born in 1936 on the island of Mer, one of the Murray
										Islands, which are located at the eastern extremity of Torres Strait. In June 1992, six
										months after his death, Mabo achieved national prominence as the successful principal
										plaintiff in the landmark High Court ruling on native land title. The High Court ruling,
										for the first time, gave legal recognition to the fact that indigenous land ownership
										existed in Australia before European settlement and that, in some cases, this land tenure
										was not subsequently extinguished by the Crown.</eac-cpf:p>
         </eac-cpf:generalContext>
      </egXML>
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <generalContext>
            <p>Edward Koiko Mabo was born in 1936 on the island of Mer, one of the Murray Islands, which are located at the eastern extremity of Torres Strait. In June 1992, six months after his death, Mabo achieved national
                           prominence as the successful principal plaintiff in the landmark High Court ruling on native land title. The High Court ruling, for the first time, gave legal recognition to the fact that indigenous land ownership
                           existed in Australia before European settlement and that, in some cases, this land tenure was notsubsequently extinguished by the Crown. </p>
            </generalContext>
         </egXML>
   </div>
</div>
