<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xml:id="structureOrGenealogy"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">Structure or Genealogy</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">A description of the internal administrative structure(s) of a corporate
							body or the genealogy of a family.</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>
         <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi> encodes information within the description area, information expressing
								the internal administrative structure(s) of a corporate body and the dates of any changes to
								that structure that are significant to understanding the way that corporate body conducted
								affairs (such as dated organization charts), or the genealogy of a family (such as a family
								tree) in a way that demonstrates the interrelationships of its members with relevant
								dates.</p>
      <p>The optional <gi>list</gi> and <gi>outline</gi> elements are used to accommodate
								greater complexity in expressing or representing the activities being described.
									<gi>citation</gi> may be used to provide a link to external documents like organizational
								charts and family trees. A simpler discursive expression of the activities may be encoded as
								one or more <gi>p</gi> elements.</p>
      <p>Genealogical and administrative structure information may alternatively be described in
								discursive form in the <gi>biogHist</gi> element (ISAAR (CPF) 5.2.2 History) and/or with
									<gi>cpfRelation</gi> elements (ISAAR (CPF) 5.3). The <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi>
								element should be used whenever separate semantic processing of information about structure
								or genealogies is required.</p>
   </div>
   
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>citation, list, outline, p</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>description</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.2.7</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <div type="mandatory">
         <p>Optional</p>
      </div>
      <div type="repeatable">
         <p>Repeatable</p>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML xml:lang="eng" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:p>Sir Edward Noel (d 1643) married Julian, daughter and co-heir of Baptists Hicks
               (d 1629), Viscount Campden, and succeeded to the viscouty of Campden and a portion of
               his father-in-law's estates. The third Viscount Campden (1612-82) married Hester Wotton,
               daughter of the second Baron Wotton. The fourth Viscount Campden (1641-1689, created
               Earl of Gainsborough, 1682) married Elizabeth Wriothesley, elder daughter of the fourth
               Earl of Southampton. Jane Noel (d 1811), sister of the fifth and sixth Earls of
               Gainsborough, married Gerard Anne Edwards of Welham Grove (Leicetershire) and had issue
               Gerard Noel Edwards (1759-1838). He married in 1780 Diana Middleton (1762-1823 suo jure
               Baroness Barham), daughter of Charles Middleton (1726-1813), created first Baronet of
               Barham Court (Kent) in 1781 and first Baron Barham in 1805. GN Edwards assumed the
               surname Noel in 1798 on inheriting the sixth Earl of Gainborough's Rutland and
               Gloucestershire estates (though not the Earl's honours, which were extinguished); and he
               later inherited his father-in-law's baronetcy. His eldest son John Noel (1781-1866)
               succeeded to the estates of his mother and his father, to his mother's barony and his
               father's baronetcy, and was created Viscount Campden and Earl of Gainsborough in
               1841.</eac-cpf:p>
         </eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy>
      </egXML>
      <egXML xml:lang="eng" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:p>The organogram of the <eac-cpf:span
               style="font-style:italic">Ministry of Culture and Tourism</eac-cpf:span> before its incorporation with the Ministry of Education and Religious Affairs, was the following:</eac-cpf:p>
            <eac-cpf:outline>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="first">
                  <eac-cpf:item>Minister of Culture and Tourism</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="second">
                  <eac-cpf:item>Deputy Minister of Culture and Tourism</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary of Tourism</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary of Sports</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary of Culture</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
               <eac-cpf:level localType="third">
                  <eac-cpf:item>General Secretary for Culture and Tourism Infrastructure</eac-cpf:item>
               </eac-cpf:level>
            </eac-cpf:outline>
         </eac-cpf:structureOrGenealogy>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>
