<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xml:id="identity"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>identity</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">Identity</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">A wrapper element for the name or names related to the identity being described within the <gi>cpfDescription</gi> element in the EAC-CPF instance. In case of multiple identities, a separate <gi>identity</gi> element is contained in each of the <gi>cpfDescription</gi> elements of instance.</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>
         <gi>identity</gi> is a container element used to group the elements necessary to encode the name or names related to the identity of the CPF entity within the <gi>cpfDescription</gi> element. Within this element the <gi>entityType</gi> element is required and specifies the type of entity (i.e., corporateBody, family, or person). One or more <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements and / or one or more <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> elements specifying names by which the identity is known is also required. An optional <gi>entityId</gi> is available for any identifiers associated with the CPF entity.</p>
      <p>All names by which the identity, being described within one <gi>cpfDescription</gi> element in the EAC-CPF instance is known are provided within this element. Within <gi>identity</gi>, each of the names, whether authorized or alternatives, should be recorded in a separate <gi>nameEntry</gi> element.</p>
      <p>In addition to needing to accommodate one or more names used for or by the CPF entity,
									<gi>identity</gi> may accommodate two or more parallel names in different languages or
								scripts. In countries where there is more than one official language, such as Canada or
								Switzerland, names of CPF entities are frequently provided in more than one language. Within
									<gi>identity</gi>, a <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> element should be used to group two or
								more <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements that represent parallel forms of the name of the CPF entity
								being described.</p>
      <p>Within <gi>identity</gi>, a <gi>descriptiveNote</gi> element may be used to record
								other information in a textual form that assists in the identification of the CPF entity.</p>
      <p>In case of multiple identities of the same entity in one EAC-CPF instance, a separate <gi>identity</gi> element is contained in each of the <gi>cpfDescription</gi> elements of the EAC-CPF instance.</p>
   </div>
   
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>descriptiveNote, entityId, entityType, nameEntry,
							nameEntryParallel</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>cpfDescription</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>identityType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:base</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.1</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <div type="mandatory">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Mandatory</p>
      </div>
      <div type="repeatable">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Non-repeatable</p>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML xml:lang="eng" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:identity xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:entityId>CLU-SC-000008</eac-cpf:entityId>
            <eac-cpf:entityType>person</eac-cpf:entityType>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry>
               <eac-cpf:part>Brown, Bob</eac-cpf:part>
               <eac-cpf:useDates>
                  <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                     <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1886">1886</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                     <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1959">1959</eac-cpf:toDate>
                  </eac-cpf:dateRange>
               </eac-cpf:useDates>
               <eac-cpf:authorizedForm>AACR2</eac-cpf:authorizedForm>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry>
               <eac-cpf:part>Brown, Robert Carlton</eac-cpf:part>
               <eac-cpf:useDates>
                  <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                     <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1886">1886</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                     <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1959">1959</eac-cpf:toDate>
                  </eac-cpf:dateRange>
               </eac-cpf:useDates>
               <eac-cpf:alternativeForm>AACR2</eac-cpf:alternativeForm>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
         </eac-cpf:identity>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>
