<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xml:id="function"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>function</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">Function</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">An element that provides information about a function, activity, role, or
							purpose performed or manifested by the CPF entity being described.</p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>A <gi>function</gi> element is a wrapper element used to encode an index term, using the
								child element <gi>term</gi>. Terms are used to identify the functions, processes,
         activities, tasks, or transactions performed by the CPF entity described in the EAC-CPF instance. They may be drawn from
								controlled vocabularies or may be natural language terms. Associated date or date range
									(<gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi> or <gi>dateSet</gi>) and place(s)
									(<gi>placeEntry</gi>) may be included to further constrain the term’s meaning. A
									<gi>descriptiveNote</gi> may be included if a textual explanation is needed.</p>
      <p>A single <gi>function</gi> element may be encoded directly within
								<gi>description</gi>. Alternatively, multiple <gi>function</gi> elements may be grouped
								within a <gi>functions</gi> element that facilitates manipulating them as a group.</p>
      <p>Functions may alternatively be described in discursive form in <gi>biogHist</gi>. The <gi>function</gi> element should be used whenever separate
								semantic processing of information about functions is required.</p>
      <p>As a further alternative, descriptions of functions may form discrete components in an
								archival descriptive system. Such descriptions should be compiled in accordance with the
								International Standard for Describing Functions (ISDF) and will typically be described in
								another encoding language. In such a system, use <gi>functionRelation</gi> to point from
								the EAC-CPF entity to the related function description.</p>
   </div>
   
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>citation, date, dateRange, dateSet, descriptiveNote, placeEntry,
							term</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>description, functions</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.2.5</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <div type="mandatory">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Optional</p>
      </div>
      <div type="repeatable">
         <p xml:lang="eng">Repeatable</p>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML xml:lang="eng" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:function xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:term>Estate ownership</eac-cpf:term>
            <eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>Social, political, and cultural role typical of landed aristocracy
										in England. The first Viscount Campden amassed a large fortune in trade in London and
										purchased extensive estates, including Exton (Rutland), and Chipping Campden
										(Gloucestershire). The Barham Court (Kent) estate was the acquisition of the first Baron
										Barham, a successful admiral and naval administrator (First Lord of the Admiralty
										1805).</eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
         </eac-cpf:function>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>
