<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema/EACCPF-TL-teiliteSchema.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:eg="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
   <!-- F. Clavaud;, Octobre 23th : a few corrections on namespace attributes and prefixes in examples -->
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title xml:lang="eng">Encoded Archival Context—Corporate Bodies, Persons, and Families (EAC-CPF)</title>
            <title xml:lang="eng" type="part2">Tag Library</title>
            <title xml:lang="fre">Contexte archivistique encodé Collectivités, personnes et familles (EAC-CPF)</title>
            <title xml:lang="fre" type="part2">Dictionnaire des balises</title>
            <respStmt xml:lang="eng">
               <resp>Prepared and maintained by the </resp>
               <!-- Update -->
               <name>Technical Subcommittee for Encoded Archival Context of the Society of American Archivists </name>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt xml:lang="fre">
               <resp>Elaboré par </resp>
               <name>le groupe de travail sur le Contexte archivistique encodé (EACWG) de la Society of American Archivists</name>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt xml:lang="fre">
               <resp>Maintenu par </resp>
               <name>la Staatsbibliothek zu Berlin</name>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt xml:lang="fre">
               <resp>traduit de l’anglais par</resp>
               <name>le groupe AFNOR CG/46/CN357/GE4</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <p xml:lang="eng">Draft</p>
            <p xml:lang="fre">version provisoire, mai 2012</p>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher xml:lang="eng">Society of American Archivists in collaboration with Staatsbibliothek zu Berlin.</publisher>
            <date when="2010"/>
            <publisher xml:lang="fre">la Society of American Archivists en collaboration avec la Staatsbibliothek de Berlin.</publisher>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p xml:lang="eng">Born digital.</p>
            <p xml:lang="fre">Nativement numérique</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <titlePage xml:lang="eng">
            <docTitle>
               <titlePart type="main">Encoded Archival Context—Corporate Bodies, Persons, and Families (EAC-CPF) Tag Library</titlePart>
            </docTitle>
            <!-- Update -->
            <docEdition>Edition 2012</docEdition>
            <byline>Prepared and maintained by the</byline>
            <!-- Update -->
            <docAuthor>Technical Subcommittee for Encoded Archival Context of the Society of American Archivists and the</docAuthor>
            <docAuthor>Staatsbibliothek zu Berlin</docAuthor>
            <docImprint>
               <docDate>1 March 2010</docDate>
            </docImprint>
         </titlePage>
         <div xml:lang="eng" type="EnglishIntroduction">
            <div>
               <head>Dedication</head>
               <!-- Updated -->
               <p>The Encoded Archival Context Working Group dedicates the 2010 EAC-CPF Schema and Tag Library to the memory of Per-Gunnar Ottosson. P-G, as he was known to his many friends around the world, played a key role in the development
                  of many international archival standards. He played a critical role in the early development of EAC, but illness and his death in 2008 prevented him from seeing the EAC-CPF work completed. He will be remembered for his
                  keen intelligence, collaborative skills, and wonderful wit. Above all, he will be fondly remembered as a friend. </p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Release and Revision Notes</head>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>While this is the final release of the Tag Library for EAC-CPF 2010, the EAC-CPF Tag Library should be considered a living document. As such, it will continue to be developed as users suggest areas in need of clarification or expansion. The Technical Subcommittee for Encoded Archival Context (TS-EAC encourages implementers to provide any queries, comments, and suggestions regarding the tag library and its content. In addition, the contribution of examples is highly encouraged. Questions, comments or examples may be directed to the EAC-CPF Tag Library Editor and co-Chair of the TS-EAC, Katherine M. Wisser (<ref target="mailto:wisser@simmons.edu">wisser [at] simmons.edu</ref>).</p>
               <p>The underlying encoding of the Tag Library is based on TEI P5 and is designed to facilitate incorporating documentation into the schema to provide guidance in XML editors. While the initial release of the Tag Library is in
                  English, the underlying encoding is designed to facilitate providing the Tag Library in additional languages at later dates.</p>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>A PDF version of the Tag Library will also be released.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Background</head>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>EAC began with a 1998 effort by Richard Szary, Wendy Duff, and Daniel Pitti to envision a standard for encoding and exchanging authoritative information about the context of archival materials. This standard would provide
                  a communication standard for the exchange of authority records based on the International Standard for Archival Authority Records—Corporate Bodies, Persons, Families (ISAAR(CPF)) and would parallel the standard for encoding
                  archival record finding aids that was found in Encoded Archival Description (EAD). As EAD enabled the practical expression of the General International Standard Archival Description (ISAD(G)), the new standard would enable the
                  expression of ISAAR(CPF). A parallel standard would preserve and strengthen the essential duality that characterizes archival description when it is presented in archival finding aids.</p>
               <p>A separate standard would pave the way to eliminating some practical problems found in the use of EAD, which had been developed as a comprehensive solution for encoding standalone finding aids—the dominant presentation
                  model—which held all forms of descriptive data about archival records. Since materials by or about a single entity might be found in many fonds or many repositories, there is much redundant effort in recording information
                  about the same entity. In addition, these duplicative efforts can result in great inconsistency, which bedevils both users, in finding and interpreting materials, and archivists, in creating accurate and complete
                  references to such entities.</p>
               <p>Yale University hosted an international meeting in 1998. The meeting was organized by Richard Szary and funded by the Digital Library Federation. The goals of the meeting were to plan the funding and development of an
                  encoding standard based on ISAAR(CPF).</p>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>In 2001, with financial assistance from the Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation, a second international working group met in Toronto. This meeting produced the Toronto Tenets, the principles that gave shape to the proposed standard. The group also established goals for the standard, mapped out the broader parameters of the Document Type Definition (DTD), and established a working group to create a fully formed syntax. The DTD achieved its Beta distribution in 2004, beginning a long testing phase as it was applied in several European and U.S. projects. Informed by the results that emerged from this testbed, the Society of American Archivists' Encoded Archival Context Working Group was formed in 2007 to carry this work forward to the creation of a standard version and expression in a schema and Tag Library. With the support of the Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation, the IBC (Instituto per I beni artistici culturali e naturali) of the Regione Emilia-Romagna, the Archivio di Stato di Bologna, OCLC Research, and the National Library of Australia, the EAC Working Group met for three days in Bologna, Italy in May 2008 to lay the foundation of the existing EAC-CPF standard. On-going work via electronic mail and conference calls continued the work started in Bologna. A review period of the final draft was offered between August and November 2009, and the completed schema was released in March 2010. The Working Group is indebted to archivists, librarians and other information professionals throughout the international community for their input, review, and testing of the schema during its development phase. In 2011, the Working Group was disbanded and SAA Council approved a charge to form the Technical Subcommittee for Encoded Archival Context (TS-EAC). The Tag Library and, in collaboration with the Schema Development Team (SDT), the EAC-CPF schema are currently maintained by the Technical Subcommittee.</p>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>Archival description includes information about the content, intellectual and physical attributes of the archival material, as well as information about the context of their creation and use. The contextual information of the creation and use of material is often complex and multi-layered and may involve individuals, families, organizations, societies, functions, activities, business processes, geographic places, events, and other entities. Primary among these entities are the corporate bodies, persons and families (CPF entities) responsible for the creation or use of material, usually organizations or persons. With information about these CPF entities, users can understand and interpret the records more fully since they will know the context within which the CPF entities operated and created and/or used the material. Information about these CPF entities can be used either as a component within descriptive approaches that fully integrate contextual information into descriptive products, as archives have traditionally done, or as an independent system that is linked to other descriptive systems and products that focus on content.</p>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>Encoded Archival Context – Corporate Bodies, Persons, and Families (EAC-CPF) primarily addresses the description of individuals, families and corporate bodies that create, preserve, use, and are responsible for and/or associated with records in a variety of ways. Over time, other types of contextual entities may evolve under the larger EAC umbrella, but currently its primary purpose is to standardize the encoding of descriptions about CPF entities to enable the sharing, discovery and display of this information in an electronic environment. It supports the linking of information about one CPF entities to other CPF entities to show/discover the relationships amongst record-creating entities and the linking to descriptions of records and other contextual entities.</p>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>EAC-CPF is a communication structure for archival contextual information for individuals, corporate bodies and families and thereby supports the exchange of ISAAR(CPF) compliant authority records. ISAAR(CPF) "determines the types of information that could be included in an archival authority record and provides guidance on how such records may be deployed in an archival descriptive system." ISAAR(CPF) also notes that "[s]uccessful automated exchange of archival authority information over computer networks is dependent upon the adoption of a suitable communication format by the repositories involved in the exchange. Encoded Archival Context (EAC) is one such communication format which supports the exchange of ISAAR(CPF) compliant archival authority data over the World Wide Web" (ISAAR(CPF), 2004, p. 12). EAC-CPF provides a mechanism for enabling the full expression of ISAAR(CPF), however it may also contain some additional elements or technical content not contained within ISAAR(CPF).</p>
               <p>Based upon the Toronto Tenets, established in 2001, the following have informed the development of the schema: <list type="ordered">
                     <head>Definitions and Uses</head>
                  <!-- Update -->
                  <item n="1">Archival context information consists of information describing the circumstances under which archival materials have been created, maintained and used. This context includes, but is not limited to, the identification and characteristics of corporate bodies, persons, and families (CPF entities) who have been the creators, users, or subjects of records, as well as the relationships amongst them.</item>
                  <!-- Update -->
                  <item n="2">Context information about CPF entities is not data that describes other information resources, but rather data that describes entities that are part of the environment in which those information resources (e.g., records) have existed.</item>
                  <!-- Update -->
                  <item n="3">The recording of context information about CPF entities in archival information systems directly supports a more complete description and understanding of records, as well as a provenance-based approach to retrieval of these records across time and domains.</item>
                  <!-- Update -->
                  <item n="4">Context information about CPF entities can also have value as an independent information resource, separate from its use in supporting the description, retrieval, and interpretation of records.</item>
                  <!-- Update -->
                  <item n="5">This model is also intended to support the exchange and sharing of context information about CPF entities, especially in those instances where repositories have holdings or interests that have context information in common.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <head>Structure and Content</head>
                     <!-- Update -->
                     <item n="6">Each instance of context information about CPF entities describes a single corporate body, person or family.</item>
                     <!-- Update -->
                     <item n="7">The model provides a framework within which the full range and depth of context information about agents can be recorded but suggests a minimum set of elements for describing an entity. The model defers recommendations for the appropriate use of other elements toguidelines developed for specific implementations.</item>
                     <!-- Update -->
                     <item n="8">The model defines a set of elements used to describe CPF entities and the structure of relationships between those elements. This structure supports the discovery, navigation and presentation of context information about CPF entitiesand the linking of that information to descriptions of resources or to other contextual entities, such as those encoded according to EAD, MARC, and similar standards.</item>
                     <item n="9">The model supports the linking of descriptions of contextual entities to digital or other surrogate representations of those entities.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <head>Technical Issues</head>
                     <item n="10">The model is expressed as an XML language to encourage platform independence and portability of information. The model may also be implemented using other approaches.</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>EAC-CPF Concepts</head>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>CPF Entities are complex. For example, one CPF entity can represent multiple identities, or a single identity can be associated with several different CPF entities. This fact necessitates the structure of a standard to account for the various ways in which CPF entities can be expressed. In order to accommodate the variety of CPF entities, EAC-CPF has adopted the following definitions:</p>
               <!-- Updated all items -->
               <list type="simple">
                  <item>SINGLE IDENTITY: one person (or corporate body or family) with a single identity represented in one EAC-CPF instance. This is the most common identity type.</item>
                  <item>MULTIPLE IDENTITY-MANY IN ONE: two or more identities (including official identities) with each represented by distinct descriptions within one EAC-CPF instance. Can be programmatically converted into Multiple Identity-One in Many.</item>
                  <item>MULTIPLE IDENTITY-ONE IN MANY: two or more identities (including official identities) each represented in two or more interrelated EAC-CPF instances. Can be programmatically converted into Multiple Identity-Many in One.</item>
                  <item>COLLABORATIVE IDENTITY: a single identity shared by two or more persons (e.g. a shared pseudonym used in creation of a collaborative work). Use Multiple Identity-One in Many.</item>
                  <item>ALTERNATIVE SET: derived EAC-CPF instance that is based on and incorporates two or more alternative EAC-CPF instances for the same entity. To be used by a consortia or a utility providing union access to authority records maintained in two or more systems by two or more agencies. Alternative EAC-CPF instances may be in different languages or in the same language.</item>
               </list>
               <!-- Update -->
               <p>EAC-CPF has been created to accommodate this variety of identities, and includes a number of ways to express complexities based on individual repository or aggregator preferences. These options reflect a design principle that underscores increased opportunity for repositories or aggregators to customize the standard for specific needs while at the same time ensuring future aggregation. These flexibilities also reflect an acknowledgement that some fundamental philosophical differences with regard to the processing of information related to separate identities of the same CPF entity exist in the international community. EAC-CPF maintains a neutral stance on those philosophical differences and instead has accommodated the various options without precluding aggregation in the future.</p>
               <p>For purposes of this tag library, agents refer to repositories or services creating or maintaining EAC-CPF records, while entities refer to those for which the records are about.</p>
            </div>
            <!-- New section -->
            <div>
               <head>Glossary</head>
               <list type="simple">
                  <item>Agent: Within the framework of the EAC-CPF schema and Tag Library, agent refers to a repository where records are managed or to individuals performing maintenance activities in the repositories. For example, <tag>agent</tag> is an element of the EAC-CPF schema within <tag>maintenanceEvent</tag>.</item>
                  <item>CPF entity: A shortcut within the framework of this Tag Library to generically designate the type of entities that are the object of a description in an EAC-CPF instance. In other words, it stands for “the corporate body, person or family being described in an EAC-CPF instance.”</item>
                  <item>Grouping: In the EAC-CPF Tag Library, the term “grouping” is used as a specialized type of wrapper for those pluralized description elements, e.g., <tag>legalStatuses</tag>, <tag>functions</tag>, etc.</item>
                  <item>Identity: Though most commonly individuals are known by their real name (the name they were given at birth), it happens that, in the course of their life, they might acquire names other than their real name. In cases where an individual has separate lines of activity, each under a different name, it might be of interest to distinguish between these names and consider them as distinct identities. From the information management standpoint, according to the policy of the repository, each of these distinct identities, though belonging to the same physical person, might either be described separately in distinct EAC-CPF instances (see EAC-CPF concepts, case of MULTIPLE IDENTITY – ONE IN MANY) or might co-exist in one EAC-CPF instance (see EAC-CPF concepts, case MULTIPLE IDENTITY – MANY IN ONE). Another case is that of a collaborative identity where several individuals chose to make themselves publicly known under a personal name (see EAC-CPF concepts, case COLLABORATIVE IDENTITY), justifying their being described in one single EAC-CPF instance.</item>
                  <item>Resource: Materials, other than CPF entities and functions’ descriptions, to which CPF instances are related.</item>
                  <item>Wrapper: In the EAC-CPF Tag Library, the term “wrapper” is used as a descriptive function for elements that can contain other elements only, e.g., <tag>legalStatus</tag>, <tag>function</tag>, and <tag>cpfDescription</tag>, etc.</item>
               </list>
               <p>The sections “Mandatory/Optional” and “Repeatable/Non-repeatable” inform about the conditions of the occurrence of an element within its parent element.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Overview of EAC-CPF Structure and Semantics</head>
               <div>
                  <head>Introduction</head>
                  <!-- Updated and added examples -->
                  <p>Each EAC-CPF instance  contains two mandatory elements, the <tag>control</tag> element and
                     either the element <tag>cpfDescription</tag> or <tag>multipleIdentities</tag>. The
                     <tag>control</tag> element contains data used in management of the EAC-CPF instance by providing administrative metadata for the description it contains. <tag>cpfDescription</tag> contains information on the
                     name structures, descriptive elements, and relationships. <tag>multipleIdentities</tag> is
                     used when there is more than one <tag>cpfDescription</tag>. These two wrapper elements contain
                     specific elements to support the functional intentions of the parent or containing
                     element.</p>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <eac-cpf:eac-cpf>
                        <eac-cpf:control>
                           [control elements]
                        </eac-cpf:control>
                        <eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                           [description elements]
                        </eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                     </eac-cpf:eac-cpf>                  
                  </egXML>
                  <p>OR</p>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <eac-cpf:eac-cpf>
                        <eac-cpf:control>
                           [control elements]
                        </eac-cpf:control>
                        <eac-cpf:multipleIdentities>
                           <eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                              [description elements]
                           </eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                           <eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                              [description elements]
                           </eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                           <eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                              [description elements]
                           </eac-cpf:cpfDescription>
                        </eac-cpf:multipleIdentities>
                     </eac-cpf:eac-cpf>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <!-- Whole div updated -->
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <tag>control</tag>
                  </head>
                  <p>The <tag>control</tag> element contains the following subelements; they are presented in the prescribed order in the EAC-CPF schema:</p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>
                        <tag>recordId</tag> - Required. Contains the one or more unique identifiers for the
                        EAC-CPF instance.</item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>otherRecordId</tag>-Optional.An element that allows the recording of additional identifiers that may be associated with the EAC-CPF instance.
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>maintenanceStatus</tag> - Required. Contains the current drafting status of the EAC-CPF instance. Values include: new, revised, deleted, cancelled, deletedSplit, or deletedReplaced.
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>publicationStatus</tag> - Optional.Contains information about the editorial status of the EAC-CPF instance.
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>maintenanceAgency</tag> -Required. Contains the name and coded information about the institution or service responsible for the creation, maintenance, and/or dissemination of the EAC-CPF instance. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>languageDeclaration</tag>-Optional.Contains coded and natural language information about the language or languages of the EAC-CPF instance. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>conventionDeclaration</tag>-Optional.Contains information on the rules used to construct the EAC-CPF instance, in particular the names formed in <tag>identity</tag> and the controlled vocabularies and thesauri used in the EAC-CPF instance.
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>localTypeDeclaration</tag>-Optional.An element used to declare local conventions used in the @localType attribute.
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>localControl</tag> - Optional. An element in which to record any administrative metadata necessary due to local practice that are not represented by the other elements in <tag>control</tag>.
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>maintenanceHistory</tag> - Required. Contains information about the date, type and events within the life cycle of an EAC-CPF instance. Contains one or more <tag>maintenanceEvent</tag> elements that document creating, importing, updating, and deletion of the description. Each maintenance event contains an agent, the type of agent (human or machine), the type of event, a description of the event, and the date of the event. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>sources</tag>-Optional. Contains information about the sources consulted in creating the description of the CPF entity or entities in the EAC-CPF instance. Contains one or more <tag>source</tag> element. 
                     </item>                  
                  </list>
               </div>
               <!-- Whole div updated -->
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <tag>cpfDescription</tag>
                  </head>
                  <p>The <tag>cpfDescription</tag>-Corporate body, person or family description, comprises the
                     description of the entity. Similar to the <tag>control</tag> element,
                     <tag>cpfDescription</tag> has four complex subelements used to describe different features
                     of the entity:</p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>
                        <tag>identity</tag> -Required. Complex structure containing the name or names used by the CPF entity over the course of the entity’s existence. Contains a repeatable <tag>nameEntry</tag> element for different names, and a repeatable <tag>nameEntryParallel</tag> element for more than one <tag>nameEntry</tag> expressed in different languages. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>description</tag> -Optional. Contains formal description elements parallel to those in ISAAR (CPF) for the description of the CPF entity. An additional <tag>localDescription</tag> allows for local implementation of additional descriptive information not included in the other <tag>description</tag> elements. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>relations</tag> -Optional. Contains one or more references to or descriptions of related corporate bodies, persons or families <tag>cpfRelation</tag>, functions <tag>functionRelation</tag>, or resources <tag>resourceRelation</tag>. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <tag>alternativeSet</tag> -Optional. Contains two or more descriptions for the same CPF entity derived from two or more systems, expressed within a single EAC-CPF instance. The <tag>alternativeSet</tag> consists of two or more <tag>setComponent</tag> elements for the descriptions. 
                     </item>                  
                  </list>
               </div>
               <!-- Whole div updated -->
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <tag>identity</tag>
                  </head>
                  <p>The most complex element in the EAC-CPF schema is the <tag>identity</tag> element. In
                     addition to needing to accommodate one or more names used for or by the CPF entity,
                     <tag>identity</tag> must accommodate two or more parallel names in different languages and/or
                     scripts. In countries where there is more than one official language, such as Canada, names of
                     corporate bodies have more than one language. The <tag>identity</tag> contains a required
                     <tag>entityType</tag> and one or more <tag>nameEntry</tag> and/or
                     <tag>nameEntryParallel</tag> elements. It also includes an optional <tag>entityId</tag> and
                     <tag>descriptiveNote</tag>. The <tag>nameEntry</tag> element is constructed of one or more
                     <tag>part</tag> elements and contains the attributes <att>scriptCode</att>,
                     <att>xml:lang</att>, <att>transliteration</att>, and <att>localType</att> to provide
                     precision about the language and script of the names if desired. It includes an optional
                     <tag>useDates</tag> element to identify dates of use of a name. <tag>nameEntryParallel</tag>,
                     which is intended for use when the same name is expressed in different languages, contains one
                     or more <tag>nameEntry</tag> elements and an optional <tag>useDates</tag> element. For
                     example, within the context of the Archive of Ontario, parallel French and English headings
                     can be designated through two parallel
                     <tag>nameEntry</tag> elements, with the two different headings being distinguished by the
                     values in the <att>xml:lang</att>.</p>
                  <p>Within <tag>identity</tag>, names represented through <tag>nameEntry</tag> or
                     <tag>nameEntryParallel</tag> may be selected as authorized or variant names. The
                     <tag>authorizedForm</tag> and <tag>alternativeForm</tag> elements are available within
                     <tag>nameEntry</tag> and <tag>nameEntryParallel</tag> elements to identify the status of the
                     name according to a particular set of rules. The content of the element is the identification
                     of those rules. Additionally, within <tag>nameEntryParallel</tag>, a single
                     <tag>nameEntry</tag> may be preferred over others. A <tag>preferredForm</tag> element is
                     available in that instance to identify the preferred form of the name according to a
                     particular set of rules. The content of the element identifies those rules.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <gi>description</gi>
                  </head>
                  <p>The <gi>description</gi> accommodates a variety of both controlled and prose descriptions of entities. The contained elements closely reflect the descriptive categories outlined in ISAAR (CPF). Descriptive elements
                     generally have a singular and plural form, the latter being used for those cases of multiple instances of a descriptive category or less formal prose description. For example, <gi>function</gi> would be used for a
                     single function term, <gi>functions</gi> will bundle more than one function descriptor or alternatively, it will allow a discursive description. Most elements within <gi>description</gi> include an optional
                        <gi>descriptiveNote</gi> element to provide explanatory text. Elements for description include:</p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>
                        <gi>existDates</gi> — dates of existence of the entity being described. Can include actual or approximate dates, using either <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>, or <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>place</gi> — includes relevant location information, optionally paired with related date information. Includes elements <gi>placeEntry</gi> and <gi>placeRole</gi> and the range of possibilities with date
                        information: <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>, <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>localDescription</gi> — An element intended to extend the descriptive categories available in a local system. Includes a <gi>term</gi> element and the range of possibilities with date information: <gi>date</gi>,
                           <gi>dateRange</gi>, <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>legalStatus</gi> — Includes the legal status of a corporate body, typically defined by authorities and granted by either a government or an authorized agency. Includes a <gi>term</gi> element and the range of
                        possibilities with date information: <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>, <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>function</gi> — Includes relevant functions, processes, activities, tasks, or transactions performed by the entity being described. Includes a <gi>term</gi> element and the range of possibilities with date
                        information: <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>, <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>occupation</gi> — Includes relevant occupations held by the entity being described. Includes a <gi>term</gi> element and the range of possibilities with date information: <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>,
                           <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>mandate</gi> — Includes relevant mandates for corporate bodies being described. Includes a <gi>term</gi> element and the range of possibilities with date information: <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>,
                           <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi> — Includes information about the structure of a corporate body or the genealogy of a person or family. Includes elements <gi>outline</gi>, <gi>list</gi>, and <gi>p</gi> to assist in
                        structuring the text.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>generalContext</gi> — Includes information about the general social and cultural context of the entity being described. Includes a <gi>term</gi> element and the range of possibilities with date information:
                           <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>, <gi>dateSet</gi>.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>biogHist</gi> — Includes discursive text providing biographical and/or historical information about the entity being described. Includes an <gi>abstract</gi> element for a brief synopsis of the full content; a
                           <gi>chronList</gi> element allows for structured date, event and optional place information. Includes <gi>list</gi>, <gi>outline</gi>, <gi>p</gi> elements to assist in structuring the text.</item>
                  </list>
                  <p> All elements in <gi>description</gi> provide a <att>localType</att> attribute to provide semantic specificity to the term being used. With the exception of <gi>existDates</gi>, <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi>,
                        <gi>generalContext</gi>, and <gi>biogHist</gi>, plural form wrapper elements are available to bundle multiple occurrences of these elements. These wrapper elements also include elements <gi>citation</gi>,
                        <gi>list</gi>, <gi>outline</gi>, and <gi>p</gi> to accommodate greater complexity in representing the description being created.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <gi>relations</gi>
                  </head>
                  <p>As a component of archival description, entity description must be brought into relation with the other descriptive components. Entity descriptions must be dynamically related to the record descriptions for which they
                     provide context, and the functions and activities in which the entities engage and that the records document. With the exception of unique relations, it is the nature of relations that they take place among entities and
                     not within them. Entities are related to other entities, to activities and functions, and to records. Similarly, activities and functions are related to other functions and activities, to creators, and to records; and
                     records are related to other records, to entities, and to functions and activities. Each entity, record, or function/activity description can thus function as a node in a set of relations.</p>
                  <p>Because relations occur between the descriptive nodes, they are most efficiently created and maintained outside of each node. A person, for example, can be related to one or more persons, organizations or families; to
                     one or more archival records, books, journals, and museum objects; and to various occupations and activities. Each of the related entities can be related to one or more other entities. To record all of these relations
                     in the description of each node is inefficient, as correction of an error would require updating two or more descriptions.</p>
                  <p>While maintaining relations independent of descriptions is efficient, when communicating descriptions between systems or to users it will be necessary to assemble or gather and represent the related descriptions using
                     descriptive surrogates. Each surrogate for a related description will optimally include both human- and machine-readable information. The human-readable information provides succinct descriptions of the related entity,
                     entity records, or function/activity sufficient to enable identification and a relevancy judgment. The machine-readable information supports a traversable link to the related description.</p>
                  <p>There are three elements for describing relations with other descriptive entities that are included in the <gi>relations</gi> element: <gi>cpfRelation</gi>, <gi>functionRelation</gi>, <gi>resourceRelation</gi>. Within
                     each of these relations elements, there are: <gi>relationEntry</gi>, <gi>objectXMLWrap</gi>, <gi>objectBinWrap</gi>, <gi>date</gi>, <gi>dateRange</gi>, <gi>dateSet</gi>, <gi>placeEntry</gi> and <gi>descriptiveNote</gi>
                     elements. Individual relations include optional attributes related to the type of relation that is being described. These include:</p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>
                        <gi>cpfRelation</gi> — includes an attribute <att>cpfRelationType</att>; values are identity, hierarchical, hierarchical-parent, hierarchical-child, temporal, temporal-earlier, temporal-later, family,
                        associative.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>functionRelation</gi> — includes an attribute <att>functionRelationType</att>; values include controls, owns, performs.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>resourceRelation</gi> — includes an attribute <att>resourceRelationType</att>; values include creatorOf, subjectOf, other.</item>
                  </list>
                  <p>Other attributes available for the relation elements include <att>lastDateTimeVerified</att>, and the suite of simple Xlink attributes.</p>
                  <p>There are two principal rationales behind the primitive or basic typing of relations. First, there is general interest in enabling coherent expression and navigation of relations as well as creation of graphic displays
                     of organizational charts, family trees, and time lines. The primitives are an experimental attempt to provide the data necessary to construct such displays. At this point, there has been no attempt to test the utility
                     of the structures with graphic displays. Second, basic information about the nature of relations is necessary in order to make the relationship intelligible to users. Given cultural and institutional differences, the
                     number of possible relation types is, in principle, unlimited. EAC-CPF designers decided, though, that to achieve a minimum level of functionality there needed to be consensus on a set of basic or primitive relation
                     types.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>xlink</head>
                  <p>The EAC-CPF schema includes support for linking to external resources using a limited subset of the xlink standard, which is defined at <ref target="http://www.w3.org/TR/xlink/">http://www.w3.org/TR/xlink/</ref>. The
                     xlink attributes can be used to create and describe links between resources. In particular they can be used to reference a richer set of relationships than those which are supported by @cpfRelationType,
                     @functionRelationType, and @resourceRelationtype. The xlink attributes are available on the following elements: <gi>citation</gi>, <gi>cpfRelation</gi>, <gi>functionRelation</gi>, <gi>resourceRelation</gi>,
                        <gi>setComponent</gi>, and <gi>source</gi>.</p>
                  <p>A more complete description of each these attributes is provided in the attributes section of the tag library, but the following information is intended to summarize how they might be used in conjunction with each
                     other.</p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Xlink Type Attribute</head>
                     <item>
                        <att>xlink:type</att> — This attribute is required if any of the other xlink attributes are used on the parent element. It takes the fixed value of 'simple' since EAC-CPF's implementation of xlink only supports
                        outbound links to one resource. If multiple outbound links are required, each link should be represented in a new parent element.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Locator Attribute</head>
                     <item>
                        <att>xlink:href</att> — This optional element may be used to provide the location of the resource that is being linked to. The link must be a valid URI.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Semantic Attributes</head>
                     <item>
                        <att>xlink:arcrole</att> — This optional element may be used on <gi>cpfRelation</gi>, <gi>functionRelation</gi>, and <gi>resourceRelation</gi> to provide a precise description of the relationship between the entity
                        described in the EAC-CPF resource and the resource to which it is linked. When used on <gi>citation</gi>, <gi>setComponent</gi>, and<gi>source</gi>, it provides an explicit and perhaps more precise description of the
                        relationship that is implied by the context of use. The value must be a valid URI.</item>
                     <item>
                        <att>xlink:role</att> — This optional element is used to provide a reference to the nature of the linked remote resource. It specifically provides a means to specify the nature of a linked resource in
                           <gi>resourceRelation</gi>, as described in ISAAR (CPF) 6.2. The value provided must be a valid URI.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Link Behavior Attributes </head>
                     <item>
                        <att>xlink:actuate</att> — This optional attributed may be used in conjunction with xlink: show to instruct an external application as to the circumstances under which the linked resource should be resolved. For
                        example, an application can be instructed to load the resource when the parent xml document is loaded or only when the page is requested by a user or application.</item>
                     <item>
                        <att>xlink:show</att> — This optional attribute may be used in conjunction with xlink:actuate to instruct an external application as to the manner in which the linked resource should be shown to the user when it is
                        resolved. For example, the application can be instructed to replace the current xml document when loading the resource or to load it in a new window or tab.</item>
                     <item>
                        <att>xlink:title</att> — This optional element may be used to provide a caption or title that an external system or application may use when presenting a link to the user.</item>
                  </list>
                  <p>Mozilla-based browsers such as Firefox are the only common client application which include native support for a limited range of xlink attributes. As a result, implementers of EAC-CPF will need to provide for the full
                     implementation of the xlink attributes using server-side instructions. One implementation example, demonstrating the intended effects of xlink usage, is provided at <ref
                        target="http://www.snee.com/xml/xlink/sxlinkdemo.xml">http://www.snee.com/xml/xlink/sxlinkdemo.xml</ref>.</p>
                  <p>The following excerpt provides one example of how xlink might be implemented in reference to an external vocabulary, to indicate that the information at the related URL describes the spouse of the person described in
                     the EAC-CPF record:</p>
                  <eg:egXML>
                     <eac-cpf:cpfRelation 
                        cpfRelationType="family" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:arcrole="http://library.illinois.edu/archives/eac-cpfRelations.html#spouseOf"
                        xlink:href="http://library.illinois.edu/archives/archon/index.php?p=creators/creator&amp;id=546" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple">
                        <eac-cpf:relationEntry>Gregory, John Milton</eac-cpf:relationEntry>
                        <eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                           <eac-cpf:p>John Milton Gregory was the husband of Louisa Allen Gregory.</eac-cpf:p>
                        </eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                     </eac-cpf:cpfRelation>
                     <eac-cpf:resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf"
                        xlink:role="http://library.illinois.edu/archives/eac-cpfRelations.html#collector" xlink:type="simple">
                        <eac-cpf:relationEntry>Collezione Fortunato Depero (Polo culturale e Galleria Museum Depero, Roverto</eac-cpf:relationEntry>
                        <eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                           <eac-cpf:p>ITA MART, Collezione Depero, Collezione d'arte, 1919-1959, Creatore della collezione, </eac-cpf:p>
                        </eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                     </eac-cpf:resourceRelation>
                  </eg:egXML>
                  <!-- perhaps an example of xlink:role on <resourceRelation> would be good. -->
                  <!-- Added, but don't think that it's right; I was thinking of the distinction that might want to be made between an author, a collector, an editor, etc. all under the umbrella of resourceRelationtype="creatorOf" -->
                  <p>The vocabulary at purl.org which is referenced above is not intended to be normative and is provided for illustrative purposes only. Over time it is hoped that communities will develop and maintain controlled
                     vocabularies to describe the nature of the relationships to the people, families, corporate bodies, resources, and functions that are described in the <gi>cpfRelation</gi>, <gi>resourceRelation</gi>, and
                        <gi>functionRelation</gi> elements. Such vocabularies could be maintained locally, nationally, or even internationally, perhaps as a continuation of the work of the EAC working group.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <att>localType</att>
                  </head>
                  <p>As an international effort, the designers of EAC-CPF are attempting to agree on as much as possible while accommodating cultural and institutional differences. The semantics and structure described above represents the
                     current semantic and structural consensus and is tied closely to ISAAR(CPF).</p>
                  <p>In addition to the element <gi>localDescription</gi>, described above, many elements may also be qualified with <att>localType</att>. This attribute is intended to enable EAC-CPF to be adapted for use in national,
                     regional, and local environments where semantics more specific than those provided in EAC-CPF may be necessary, or where descriptive categories not specifically addressed in EAC-CPF are necessary.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div xml:lang="fre" type="TranslatedIntroduction">
            <div>
               <head>Composition du groupe des traducteurs, membres du AFNOR CG46/CN357/GE4</head>
               <p>CG 46 Information et documentation (président : Pierre Fuzeau)</p>
               <p>CN 357 Modélisation, production et accès aux documents (présidente : Françoise Bourdon)</p>
               <p>GE 4 Données d'autorité (animatrice : Anila Angjeli)</p>
               <list>
                  <item>Anila Angjeli (Bibliothèque nationale de France)</item>
                  <item>Vincent Boulet (Bibliothèque nationale de France)</item>
                  <item>Florence Clavaud (École nationale des chartes)</item>
                  <item>Danis Habib (Archives nationales)</item>
                  <item>Aline Locker (Bibliothèque nationale de France)</item>
                  <item>Denise Ogilvie (Archives nationales)</item>
                  <item>Florent Palluault (Ministère de la culture et de la communication / Service du livre et de la lecture)</item>
                  <item>Claire Sibille (Ministère de la culture et de la communication / Service interministériel des archives de France)</item>
                  <item>Sébastien Studer (Ministère de la culture et de la communication / Service interministériel des archives de France)</item>
                  <item>Pascal Tanésie (Archives nationales)</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <!--FC<div>
            <head/>
         </div>-->
            <div>
               <head>De l’EACWG au TS-EAC-CPF</head>
               <p>Le groupe de travail sur le Contexte archivistique encodé (EACWG), mandaté en 2007 par la Society of American Archivists (Société des archivistes américains - SAA) pour réviser la DTD EAC bêta, a accompli sa tâche en
                  développant le nouveau schéma EAC-CPF. Le schéma et son dictionnaire de balises ont été publiés en février 2010. L’EAC-CPF a été adopté comme un standard de la SAA en novembre 2010, ce qui a entraîné la dissolution du
                  EACWG.</p>
               <p>Cette même année a connu la réorganisation, au sein du Comité des normes de la SAA, des instances chargées de la gestion des standards d’encodage. Trois sous-comités techniques ont été créés pour permettre la gestion et
                  l’évolution cohérentes et coordonnées des deux standards d’encodage, l’EAD et l’EAC-CPF : le sous-comité technique pour l’EAD (TS-EAD), le sous-comité technique pour l’EAC-CPF (TS-EAC-CPF) et l’équipe de développement des
                  schémas (SDT). Le TS-EAC-CPF a été mandaté pour gérer et faire évoluer l’EAC-CPF en janvier 2011 pour une durée de cinq ans renouvelable.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Introduction à la présente traduction française</head>
               <p>La traduction française du dictionnaire des balises de l’EAC-CPF a été réalisée par un groupe de travail spécifique, composé de membres du groupe AFNOR CG46/CN357/GE4. </p>
               <p>Au même titre que l’original, la traduction du dictionnaire des balises ne doit pas être considérée comme figée. Son contenu comme son format de présentation sont susceptibles d’évoluer prochainement. Les objectifs de la
                  présente édition sont de mettre rapidement à la disposition des utilisateurs un outil de travail permettant d’appliquer plus facilement le schéma, de fournir un document utilisable pour des formations et, plus largement,
                  d’aider à répandre l’utilisation du schéma dans la communauté francophone des archivistes, des bibliothécaires ou d’autres métiers qui en auraient besoin. </p>
               <p>Les exemples figurant dans la version d’origine ont été conservés tels quels. Des exemples complets de notices d’autorité encodées en EAC-CPF sont fournis en annexe de la présente édition et également sous forme de
                  fichiers xml téléchargeables.</p>
               <p>La traduction ne se substitue pas à d’éventuelles règles de bonnes pratiques d’utilisation de l’EAC-CPF en France qui pourront être établies ultérieurement.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Dédicace</head>
               <p>Le Groupe de travail sur le Contexte Archivistique Encodé dédie le schéma EAC-CPF et son dictionnaire de balises à la mémoire de Per-Gunnar Ottosson. P-G, comme l’appelaient ses nombreux amis un peu partout dans le monde,
                  a joué un rôle crucial dans le développement de nombreuses normes archivistiques internationales. Il a joué un rôle important dans les premiers développements de l’EAC, mais sa maladie et son décès en 2008 l’ont empêché de
                  voir l’accomplissement du travail sur l’EAC-CPF. Nous n’oublierons pas sa vive intelligence, ses capacités collaboratives et son esprit d’exception. Mais avant tout, nous nous souviendrons de lui comme d’un ami.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Notes sur la publication et la révision</head>
               <p>Le dictionnaire des balises de l’EAC-CPF doit être considéré comme un document vivant. En tant que tel, il continuera à évoluer en tenant compte des propositions venant des utilisateurs pour clarifier ou approfondir les
                  explications. Le Groupe de travail sur l’EAC encourage les utilisateurs à poser toute question, à exprimer des commentaires et des suggestions concernant le dictionnaire des balises et son contenu. De plus, l’apport
                  d’exemples est fortement encouragé. Les questions, commentaires ou exemples peuvent être adressés à la présidente du Groupe de travail EAC Katherine M. Wisser (wisser [at] simmons.edu). Le dictionnaire des balises est
                  encodé en TEI P5 et est conçu pour faciliter l’incorporation de la documentation dans le schéma pour fournir une aide dans les éditeurs XML. Si la publication initiale du dictionnaire des balises est en anglais, son
                  encodage est conçu pour faciliter l’intégration ultérieure d’autres versions linguistiques.</p>
               <p>Une version PDF du Dictionnaire des balises sera également publiée ultérieurement.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Historique et principes généraux</head>
               <p>L’histoire de l’EAC commence en 1998 avec une tentative de Richard Szary, Wendy Duff et Daniel Pitti pour concevoir un standard destiné à l’encodage et à l’échange de l’information d’autorité relative au contexte des
                  documents d’archives. Le but était d’offrir un standard de communication pour l’échange des notices d’autorité établies en appliquant la Norme internationale sur les notices d'autorité utilisées pour les Archives relatives
                  aux collectivités, aux personnes et aux familles (ISAAR(CPF)) et qui serait appliqué en parallèle du standard pour l’encodage des instruments de recherche archivistiques – la Description archivistique encodée (EAD). Tout
                  comme l’EAD a permis l’expression pratique de la Norme générale et internationale de description archivistique (ISAD (G)), le nouveau standard permettrait celle de l’ISAAR (CPF). Un standard parallèle préserverait et
                  renforcerait la double caractéristique de la description archivistique telle qu’elle est présentée dans les instruments de recherche.</p>
               <p>Un standard distinct permettrait l’élimination de quelques problèmes pratiques rencontrés dans l’utilisation de l’EAD qui a été élaboré comme une solution globale pour encoder des instruments de recherche autonomes – en
                  tant que modèle de présentation dominant – contenant les données descriptives de toute forme sur les archives. Étant donné que les documents produits par ou sur une même entité peuvent se trouver dans plusieurs fonds ou
                  dans plusieurs institutions de conservation, les efforts pour enregistrer les informations relatives à la même entité sont multipliés. Qui plus est, la multiplication des descriptions porte le risque de grandes
                  incohérences qui peuvent désorienter à la fois les utilisateurs dans la recherche et l’interprétation des documents et les archivistes dans la création des descriptions pertinentes et complètes pour ces entités.</p>
               <p>En 1998 l’Université de Yale accueillit une réunion internationale. Cette réunion avait été organisée par Richard Szary et financée par la Digital Library Federation (Fédération des bibliothèques numériques). Elle avait
                  pour but de programmer le financement et l’élaboration d’un standard d’encodage fondé sur ISAAR(CPF).</p>
               <p>En 2001, avec l’aide financière de la Fondation Gladys Krieble Delmas, un deuxième groupe de travail international s’est réuni à Toronto. Le résultat de cette réunion a été la rédaction du document connu comme les
                  Principes de Toronto, principes qui ont constitué le fondement du standard EAC. Le groupe a également fixé les objectifs du standard, tracé les grandes lignes de la DTD et mis sur pied un groupe pour l’élaboration d’une
                  syntaxe complète. La publication de la version bêta de la DTD en 2004 a marqué le début d’une longue période de tests ; elle a été appliquée dans plusieurs projets en Europe et aux États-Unis. Le recueil des remarques
                  émanant de ces expériences de terrain a conduit à la création en 2007 du Groupe de travail sur le Contexte archivistique encodé de la SAA afin d’axer la réflexion vers la création d’un standard exprimé en schéma et
                  documenté par un Dictionnaire de balises. Avec l’appui de la Fondation Gladys Krieble Delmas, de l’Institut des biens culturels (Instituto per i beni artistici culturali et naturali) de la région Émilie-Romagne, des
                  Archives d’État de Bologne, de OCLC Recherche et de la Bibliothèque nationale d’Australie, le Groupe de travail EAC s’est réuni trois jours à Bologne, en Italie, en mai 2008 pour jeter les fondements du présent standard
                  EAC-CPF. Le travail commencé à Bologne s’est poursuivi par le biais de courriers électroniques et de conférences téléphoniques. Le projet final a été soumis à une dernière révision d’août à septembre 2009 et la version
                  finalisée du schéma a été publiée en février 2010. Le Groupe de travail est redevable à toute la communauté internationale des archivistes et des bibliothécaires pour ses contributions, révisions et tests du schéma durant
                  sa phase d’élaboration.</p>
               <p>Les descriptions archivistiques comprennent des informations sur le contenu, sur les caractéristiques intellectuelles et physiques des documents d’archives de même que des informations sur le contexte de leur production et
                  de leur utilisation. Le contexte de la production et de l’usage des documents d’archives est complexe. Il est à plusieurs niveaux et peut impliquer des individus, des familles, des organisations, des sociétés, des
                  fonctions, des activités, des processus de travail, des lieux géographiques, des évènements et d’autres entités. Parmi ces entités, les agents (personnes morales ou physiques) responsables de la production et de
                  l’utilisation des documents d’archives sont essentiels. Les informations sur ces agents permettent aux utilisateurs de mieux comprendre et interpréter les descriptions, car elles permettent de connaître le contexte dans
                  lequel les agents ont opéré et ont créé et/ou utilisé les documents d’archives. Les informations contextuelles sur ces agents peuvent être utilisées soit comme une partie composante de la description des documents
                  eux-mêmes qui intègre les informations contextuelles dans les instruments de recherche, selon la pratique traditionnelle des archives, soit comme un système indépendant relié à d’autres systèmes et produits descriptifs
                  centrés sur les contenus.</p>
               <p>Le Contexte archivistique encodé - collectivités, personnes et familles (EAC-CPF) traite en premier lieu des individus, familles et collectivités qui produisent, conservent, utilisent et ont la responsabilité des documents
                  ou y sont associés de plusieurs manières. Dans l’avenir, il sera possible de décrire d’autres types d’entités contextuelles sous l’appellation générique EAC, mais à présent l’objectif est de normaliser l’encodage des
                  descriptions des agents afin de permettre le partage, la découverte et la présentation de ces informations dans un environnement électronique. EAC-CPF permet de lier les informations sur un agent à celles d’autres agents
                  afin de présenter/découvrir les relations entre les producteurs et de lier ces informations aux descriptions de documents et à d’autres entités contextuelles.</p>
               <p>L’EAC-CPF permet de communiquer des informations contextuelles archivistiques structurées pour les individus, collectivités et familles. Elle permet d’échanger des notices d’autorité conformes à ISAAR (CPF), qui
                  « détermine la nature des informations à inclure dans une notice d’autorité archivistique, et propose des orientations sur la manière d’intégrer ces notices dans un système de description contrôlé ». ISAAR (CPF) précise
                  également que « le succès de l’échange automatisé de ces informations par l’intermédiaire des réseaux informatiques dépend de l’adoption d’un bon format de communication par tous les services d’archives concernés.
                  L’Encodage du contexte archivistique/ Encoded Archival Context (EAC) est un tel format. Il permet l’échange sur le Web de notices d’autorité établies conformément à la norme ISAAR(CPF). » (ISAAR (CPF), 2004, § 4.13).
                  L’EAC-CPF fournit un mécanisme permettant d’exprimer pleinement ISAAR (CPF) ; il peut toutefois contenir d’autres éléments additionnels ou des éléments techniques non contenus dans ISAAR (CPF).</p>
               <p>L’élaboration du schéma, qui s’est appuyée sur les Principes de Toronto, établis en 2001, a été guidée par les principes suivants :</p>
               <list>
                  <head>Définitions et usages</head>
                  <item>Les informations contextuelles archivistiques consistent à décrire les circonstances dans lesquelles les documents archivistiques ont été produits, gérés et utilisés. Ce contexte comprend, entre autres,
                     l’identification et les caractéristiques des personnes, organisations et familles (agents) qui ont été les producteurs, utilisateurs ou sujets des archives, de même que les relations qu’ils entretiennent.</item>
                  <item>Les informations contextuelles sur les agents ne décrivent pas d’autres ressources d’information, mais plutôt les entités qui font partie de l’environnement dans lequel ces ressources d’information (par exemple les
                     archives) ont existé.</item>
                  <item>L’intégration des informations contextuelles sur les agents dans les systèmes d’information archivistiques permet une description et une compréhension plus complète des documents. De même, elle facilite la recherche
                     des archives par provenance à travers différentes époques et différents domaines.</item>
                  <item>Les informations contextuelles sur les agents peuvent également être considérées comme une ressource d’information indépendante, séparée de leur utilisation en tant que complément de la description, de la recherche
                     et de l’interprétation des documents.</item>
                  <item>Ce modèle vise également à contribuer à l’échange et au partage des informations contextuelles sur les agents, en particulier lorsque celles-ci sont communes aux collections ou aux centres d’intérêt de différentes
                     institutions de conservation.</item>
               </list>
               <list>
                  <head>Structure et contenu</head>
                  <item>Chaque instance d’information contextuelle sur les agents décrit une seule entité.</item>
                  <item>Le modèle fournit un cadre qui permet d’enregistrer la totalité et la profondeur des informations contextuelles sur les agents et suggère un ensemble minimum d’éléments de description d’une entité, mais laisse le
                     soin d’émettre des recommandations pour une utilisation appropriée d’autres éléments aux manuels qui seront réalisés dans le cadre d’applications spécifiques.</item>
                  <item>Le modèle définit un ensemble d’éléments à utiliser pour décrire des agents ainsi que la structure des relations entre eux. Ces éléments et cette structure permettent de découvrir, de parcourir et de présenter les
                     informations contextuelles sur les agents. Ils permettent également de lier ces informations aux descriptions des documents d’archives ou à celles d’autres entités contextuelles, en particulier à celles qui sont
                     encodées en EAD, en MARC ou dans d’autres formats de ce type.</item>
                  <item>Le modèle permet de relier les descriptions des entités contextuelles aux représentations numériques ou autres substituts de ces entités.</item>
               </list>
               <list>
                  <head>Questions techniques</head>
                  <item>Le modèle est exprimé en langage XML pour favoriser la portabilité de l’information ainsi que son indépendance par rapport à toute plateforme. Il peut également être implémenté en utilisant d’autres approches.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Les concepts de l’EAC-CPF</head>
               <p>Les agents sont complexes. Par exemple, un agent peut avoir des identités multiples, ou une seule identité peut également être associée à plusieurs agents. La structure du standard doit donc prendre en compte les
                  différents modes de représentation des agents. Pour refléter la diversité des agents, plusieurs concepts sont définis :</p>
               <p>UNE SEULE IDENTITE : une personne (ou collectivité ou famille) avec une identité unique représentée dans une instance EAC-CPF. (Cas le plus fréquent).</p>
               <p>IDENTITE MULTIPLE – PLUSIEURS EN UNE : deux identités ou davantage (y compris les identités officielles) qui font chacune l’objet de descriptions différenciées dans une même instance EAC-CPF. Peut être converti par
                  programme en Identité multiple – une en plusieurs. (Cas moins fréquent bien que pas très rare).</p>
               <p>IDENTITE MULTIPLE – UNE EN PLUSIEURS : deux identités ou davantage (y compris les identités officielles), représentées dans des instances EAC-CPF distinctes, reliées entre elles. Peut être converti par programme en
                  Identité multiple – plusieurs en une. (Cas moins fréquent bien que pas très rare).</p>
               <p>ENSEMBLE ALTERNATIF : instance EAC-CPF dérivée, basée sur et incorporant deux ou plusieurs instances EAC-CPF pour la même entité. À utiliser par un consortium ou un service offrant un accès collectif aux notices d’autorité
                  gérées dans deux ou plusieurs systèmes gérés par deux ou plusieurs agences. Les instances EAC-CPF alternatives peuvent être dans une langue unique ou dans plusieurs langues.</p>
               <p>IDENTITE COLLABORATIVE : une seule identité partagée par deux ou plusieurs personnes (par exemple un pseudonyme collectif utilisé dans la création d’une œuvre de collaboration). Utiliser Identité multiple – une en
                  plusieurs. (Rare).</p>
               <p>L’EAC-CPF a été créée pour satisfaire ces différents cas d’identités et offre un certain nombre de possibilités pour exprimer les complexités liées aux pratiques de chaque entrepôt de données ou agrégateur. Ces options
                  reflètent un principe de conception marqué par la volonté d’offrir aux entrepôts de données ou aux agrégateurs de grandes possibilités d’adaptation du standard pour leurs besoins spécifiques tout en gardant la possibilité
                  d’une future agrégation de données. Cette souplesse prend également en compte l’existence, dans la communauté internationale, de conceptions fondamentalement différentes en matière de description des identités. L’EAC-CPF
                  s’en tient à une position neutre par rapport à ces différences de philosophie et s’efforce de répondre aux différents choix sans exclure la possibilité d’une future agrégation.</p>
               <p>Au sein du dictionnaire de balises du schéma EAC-CPF, le terme « agents » désigne les institutions ou services producteurs de notices EAC-CPF, alors que le terme « entités » fait référence aux collectivités, personnes ou
                  familles sur lesquelles portent les notices.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Vue d’ensemble de la structure et de la sémantique de l’EAC-CPF</head>
               <div>
                  <head>Introduction</head>
                  <p>Chaque instance EAC-CPF contient deux éléments obligatoires, l’élément Contrôle <gi>control</gi> d’une part et, soit l’élément Description de collectivité, de personne ou de famille <gi>cpfDescription</gi>, soit
                     l’élément Identités multiples <gi>multipleIdentities</gi> d’autre part. L’élément <gi>control</gi> contient des données utilisées pour le contrôle de la description de l’entité et précisant le contexte pour cette
                     description. L’élément <gi>cpfDescription</gi> contient des informations sur la/les structure(s) du/des nom(s), sur les éléments descriptifs et les relations. L’élément <gi>multipleIdentities</gi> est utilisé lorsqu’il
                     y a plus d’un élément <gi>cpfDescription</gi>. Ces deux éléments englobants contiennent des éléments spécifiques permettant de supporter les objectifs fonctionnels de l’élément parent ou contenant.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <gi>control</gi>
                  </head>
                  <p>L’élément <gi>control</gi> contient les sous-éléments suivants :</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>recordId</gi> - Identifiant de la notice. Contient un ou plusieurs identifiant(s) unique(s) pour l’instance EAC-CPF. Obligatoire.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>maintenanceAgency</gi> - Agence de maintenance. Nom et information codée sur l’institution ou le service responsable de la création, de la gestion et/ou de la diffusion de l’instance EAC-CPF. Obligatoire.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>maintenanceStatus</gi> - État de la notice. Contient le statut du traitement de l’instance EAC-CPF dans le processus de travail courant. Les valeurs sont : "new" (nouveau), "revised" (révisée), "deleted"
                     (supprimée), "cancelled" (annulée), "deletedSplit" (supprimée et scindée), "deletedReplaced" (supprimée et remplacée) ou "derived" (dérivée). Obligatoire.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>maintenanceHistory</gi> - Historique des interventions. Contient des informations sur la date, le type d’agent et les évènements relatifs au cycle de vie d’une instance EAC-CPF. Contient un ou plusieurs élément(s)
                     Intervention <gi>maintenanceEvent</gi> qui permettent de documenter la création, l’import, la mise à jour et la suppression de la description. Chaque intervention est précisée par le nom d’un agent, le type de l’agent
                     (humain ou machine), le type de l’évènement, une description de l’évènement et la date de l’évènement. Obligatoire.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>publicationStatus</gi> - État de publication. Contient des informations sur le statut éditorial de l’instance EAC-CPF. Facultatif.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>languageDeclaration</gi> - Déclaration de la langue. Contient des informations sous forme codée et en langage naturel sur la langue de rédaction de l’instance EAC-CPF. Obligatoire.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>sources</gi> - Sources. Contient des informations sur les sources consultées pour la création de la description de l’entité ou des entités dans l’instance EAC-CPF. Contient un ou plusieurs élément(s) Source
                        <gi>source</gi>. Obligatoire.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>conventionDeclaration</gi> - Déclaration de règle ou de convention. Contient des informations sur les règles utilisées pour élaborer l’instance EAC-CPF, en particulier les noms structurés dans l’élément Identité
                        <gi>identity</gi>, ainsi que des informations sur les vocabulaires contrôlés et les thésaurus utilisés dans l’instance EAC-CPF. Facultatif.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>otherRecordId</gi> - Identifiant d’une autre notice. Élément permettant l’enregistrement d’autres identifiants additionnels pouvant être associés à l’instance EAC-CPF. Facultatif.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>localControl</gi> - Contrôle local. Élément permettant d’enregistrer toute information de contrôle nécessaire pour les pratiques locales et qui n’est pas représenté par d’autres éléments dans <gi>control</gi>.
                     Facultatif.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>localTypeDeclaration</gi> - Déclaration d’une convention locale. Élément utilisé pour déclarer des conventions locales utilisées dans l’attribut <att>localType</att>.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <gi>cpfDescription</gi>
                  </head>
                  <p>L’élément <gi>cpfDescription</gi> - Description de collectivité, personne ou famille, comprend les éléments de la description de l’entité. Comme l’élément Contrôle <gi>control</gi>, <gi>cpfDescription</gi> contient
                     plusieurs sous-éléments utilisés pour décrire les différentes caractéristiques de l’entité.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>identity</gi> - Identité. Structure complexe contenant le ou les noms utilisés par l’entité tout au long de son existence. Contient un élément répétable Forme du nom <gi>nameEntry</gi> pour encoder les différents
                     noms et un élément répétable Formes parallèles du nom <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> pour encoder plusieurs éléments <gi>nameEntry</gi> exprimés en différentes langues. Obligatoire.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>description</gi> - Description. Contient les éléments descriptifs formels analogues à ceux d’ISAAR (CPF) pour la description de l’entité. Un élément additionnel Description locale <gi>localDescription</gi> permet
                     d’introduire dans les implémentations locales des informations descriptives additionnelles qui ne sont pas comprises dans d’autres éléments de l’élément <gi>description</gi>. Facultatif.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>relations</gi> - Relations. Contient une ou plusieurs références à des collectivités, personnes ou familles en relation avec l’entité décrite ou des descriptions de celles-ci, encodées dans un élément
                        <gi>cpfRelation</gi>, des références à des fonctions ou des descriptions de celles-ci encodées dans un élément <gi>functionRelation</gi>, ou bien des références à des ressources ou des descriptions de celles-ci
                     encodées dans un élément <gi>resourceRelation</gi>. Facultatif.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>alternativeSet</gi> - Ensemble alternatif. Contient deux ou plusieurs notices d’autorité relatives à la même entité, dérivées de deux ou plusieurs systèmes d’autorité et exprimées au sein d’une seule instance
                     EAC-CPF. L’élément <gi>alternativeSet</gi> comprend deux ou plusieurs éléments Composant de l’ensemble <gi>setComponent</gi> permettant d’inclure les notices d’autorité. Facultatif.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <gi>identity</gi>
                  </head>
                  <p>L’élément le plus complexe dans le schéma EAC-CPF est l’élément <gi>identity</gi>. Outre le fait de contenir le(s) nom(s) utilisé(s) pour ou par l’entité, <gi>identity</gi> permet la présence de deux ou plusieurs formes
                     parallèles du nom dans des langues et/ou dans des écritures différentes. Dans les pays qui ont plus d’une langue officielle, tel que le Canada, les noms des collectivités sont exprimés dans plus d’une langue. L’élément
                        <gi>identity</gi> contient un élément obligatoire Type de l’entité <gi>entityType</gi>, un ou plusieurs élément(s) Forme du nom <gi>nameEntry</gi> et/ou un ou plusieurs élément(s) Formes parallèles du nom
                        <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>. Il comprend également un élément facultatif Identifiant de l’entité <gi>entityId</gi> et un autre élément facultatif Note descriptive <gi>descriptiveNote</gi>. L’élément <gi>nameEntry</gi>
                     est composé d’un ou de plusieurs éléments Partie <gi>part</gi> et contient les attributs Code de l’écriture <att>scriptCode</att>, XML langue <att>xml:lang</att>, Translittération <att>translitteration</att> et Type
                     local <att>localType</att> afin de préciser la langue et l’écriture des noms si on le souhaite. Il comprend un élément Dates d’utilisation <gi>useDates</gi> pour identifier les dates d’utilisation d’un nom. L’élément
                     Formes parallèles du nom <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, qui est utilisé lorsque le même nom est exprimé en différentes langues, contient un ou plusieurs élément(s) <gi>nameEntry</gi> et un élément facultatif
                        <gi>useDates</gi>. Par exemple, dans le contexte des Archives de l’Ontario, des formes parallèles du nom en français et en anglais peuvent être encodées en introduisant le code de l’institution par deux éléments
                     parallèles <gi>nameEntry</gi>, les deux formes du nom se distinguant par les valeurs données dans l’attribut <att>xml:lang</att>.</p>
                  <p>Au sein de l’élément <gi>identity</gi>, les formes du nom indiquées dans les éléments <gi>nameEntry</gi> ou <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> peuvent être déclarées comme formes autorisées ou comme variantes de nom. Au sein de
                     l’élément <gi>nameEntry</gi> et de l’élément <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, les éléments Forme autorisée <gi>authorizedForm</gi> et Forme alternative <gi>alternativeForm</gi> permettent d’identifier le statut du nom selon
                     les règles appliquées. Chacun de ces éléments doit préciser les règles utilisées. De plus, au sein d’un même élément <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, un seul élément <gi>nameEntry</gi> peut être déclaré comme préféré aux
                     autres. Dans ce cas, un élément Forme préférée <gi>preferredForm</gi> permet d’identifier la forme préférée du nom selon les règles appliquées. Le contenu de l’élément <gi>preferredForm</gi> précise les règles
                     utilisées.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <gi>description</gi> </head>
                  <p>L’élément Description <gi>description</gi> accueille toute une variété d’éléments servant à décrire l’entité, tant sous forme contrôlée qu’en texte libre. Les éléments contenus dans <gi>description</gi> reflètent
                     étroitement les catégories descriptives de l’ISAAR (CPF). Les éléments descriptifs sont disponibles généralement au singulier et au pluriel ; la forme au pluriel étant utilisée pour distinguer les instances multiples
                     d’une catégorie descriptive ou d’une description peu formalisée en texte libre. Par exemple l’élément Fonction <gi>function</gi> est utilisé pour un seul terme désignant une fonction, tandis que l’élément Fonctions
                        <gi>functions</gi> encapsule plus d’un descripteur de fonction ou, alternativement, une description discursive. La plupart des éléments contenus dans <gi>description</gi> contiennent un élément facultatif Note
                     descriptive <gi>descriptiveNote</gi> pour fournir des explications textuelles. Les éléments descriptifs sont :</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>existDates</gi> - Dates d’existence de l’entité décrite. Peut contenir des dates exactes ou approximatives en utilisant les éléments Date <gi>date</gi>, ou Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, ou Ensemble de
                     dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>place</gi> - Lieu. Contient les informations pertinentes relatives à la localisation, couplées, si besoin est, avec une ou plusieurs dates associées au lieu. Comprend les éléments Entrée du lieu <gi>placeEntry</gi>
                     ainsi que les éléments permettant d’encoder la/les date(s) : Date <gi>date</gi>, Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>localDescription</gi> - Description locale. Un élément permettant d’inclure des éléments de description particuliers aux systèmes locaux. Comprend un élément Terme <gi>term</gi> ainsi que les éléments permettant
                     d’encoder la/les date(s) associée(s) Date <gi>date</gi>, Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>legalStatus</gi> - Statut juridique. Contient les informations sur le statut juridique d’une collectivité, tel qu’il est défini par un organisme d’autorité, par un gouvernement ou par une agence habilitée à cet
                     effet. Comprend un élément Terme <gi>term</gi> ainsi que les éléments permettant d’encoder la/les date(s) Date <gi>date</gi>, Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>function</gi> - Fonction. Contient les informations sur les fonctions, procédures, activités, tâches ou transactions exercées par l’entité décrite. Comprend un élément Terme <gi>term</gi> ainsi que les éléments
                     permettant d’encoder la/les date(s) Date <gi>date</gi>, Intervalles de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>occupation</gi> - Occupation. Contient les informations sur les activités de l’entité décrite. Comprend un élément Terme <gi>term</gi> ainsi que les éléments permettant d’encoder la/les date(s) associée(s) Date
                        <gi>date</gi>, Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>mandate</gi> - Texte de référence. Contient les informations sur les textes de référence relatifs aux collectivités décrites. Comprend un élément Terme <gi>term</gi> ainsi que les éléments permettant d’encoder
                     la/les date(s) associée(s) Date <gi>date</gi>, Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi> - Organisation interne ou généalogie. Contient les informations sur la structure d’une collectivité ou la généalogie d’une personne ou d’une famille. Comprend les éléments Vue d’ensemble
                        <gi>outline</gi>, Liste <gi>list</gi> et Paragraphe <gi>p</gi> pour aider à structurer le texte.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>generalContext</gi> - Contexte général. Contient les informations sur le contexte général, social et culturel de l’entité décrite. Comprend un élément Terme <gi>term</gi> ainsi que les éléments permettant d’encoder
                     la/les date(s) associée(s) Date <gi>date</gi>, Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates <gi>dateSet</gi>.</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>biogHist</gi> - Biographie ou histoire. Contient les informations biographiques et/ou historiques sur l’entité décrite, sous forme de texte libre. Comprend un élément Résumé <gi>abstract</gi> pour un bref synopsis
                     du contenu informationnel de l’élément. Un élément Liste chronologique <gi>chronList</gi> permet de fournir des informations structurées sur les dates, les évènements et des informations facultatives sur les lieux.
                     Comprend les éléments Liste <gi>list</gi>, Vue d’ensemble <gi>outline</gi> et Paragraphe <gi>p</gi> pour aider à structurer le texte.</p>
                  <p>Tous les éléments inclus dans <gi>description</gi> admettent un attribut <att>localType</att> pour permettre d’exprimer les spécificités sémantiques locales des termes utilisés. À l’exception des éléments Dates
                     d’existence <gi>existDates</gi>, Organisation interne ou généalogie <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi>, Contexte général <gi>generalContext</gi> et Biographie ou histoire <gi>biogHist</gi>, les autres éléments existent sous
                     une forme au pluriel. Ce sont des éléments englobants permettant de réunir des occurrences multiples de chacun des éléments correspondants exprimés au singulier. Ces éléments englobants comprennent également les
                     éléments Citation <gi>citation</gi>, Liste <gi>list</gi>, Plan <gi>outline</gi> et Paragraphe <gi>p</gi> pour représenter une description sous une forme plus complexe.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <gi>relations</gi>
                  </head>
                  <p>En tant que composante de la description archivistique, la description de l’entité doit être mise en relation avec d’autres composantes de la même description. Les descriptions des entités doivent être reliées de façon
                     dynamique aux descriptions des documents d’archives pour lesquelles elles fournissent des informations contextuelles et aux fonctions et activités que les entités exercent et qui sont documentées par les notices. À
                     l’exception des relations uniques, il est dans la nature des relations d’être établies entre les entités et non pas en leur propre sein. Les entités sont reliées à d’autres entités, à des activités et fonctions et à des
                     descriptions. De même, les activités et les fonctions sont reliées à d’autres fonctions et activités, aux producteurs de documents d’archives, à des entités et, à leur tour, les documents d’archives sont reliés à
                     d’autres documents d’archives, à des entités et à des fonctions et activités. Chaque description d’entité, de documents ou de fonction ou activité peut ainsi fonctionner comme un nœud dans un réseau de relations.</p>
                  <p>Les relations se produisant entre les nœuds descriptifs, il est plus efficace de les créer et de les maintenir en dehors de chaque nœud. Par exemple, une personne peut être reliée à une ou plusieurs personnes,
                     collectivités ou familles, à un ou plusieurs document(s) d’archives, livres, périodiques et objets muséaux et à différentes activités et occupations. Chacune des entités en relation peut être elle-même mise en relation
                     avec une ou plusieurs autres entités. Enregistrer toutes ces relations dans la description de chaque nœud n’est pas efficace, car la correction d’une erreur demanderait la mise à jour de deux ou plusieurs
                     descriptions.</p>
                  <p>Bien qu’il soit judicieux de maintenir les relations indépendantes des descriptions, il est nécessaire, pour l’échange des descriptions entre les systèmes, de rassembler les descriptions en relation et de les
                     représenter en utilisant des substituts de description. Chaque substitut pour une description en relation comprend, dans l’idéal, des informations lisibles à la fois par les humains et par les machines. Les informations
                     lisibles par les humains fourniront une description succincte de l’entité en relation, des archives produites par l’entité, ou de sa fonction/activité. Elles seront suffisantes pour permettre l’identification et la
                     pertinence des informations. Les informations lisibles par les machines permettent l’établissement et l’actionnement du lien vers la description en relation.</p>
                  <p>Trois éléments permettent de décrire les relations avec d’autres entités pouvant être comprises dans l’élément <gi>relations</gi> : Relation avec une collectivité, une personne ou une famille <gi>cpfRelation</gi>,
                     Relation avec une fonction <gi>functionRelation</gi>, Relation avec une ressource <gi>ressourceRelation</gi>. Chacun de ces éléments permettant d’encoder des relations contient les éléments : Forme du nom de l’entité en
                     relation <gi>relationEntry</gi>, Enveloppe d’objet XML <gi>objectXMLWrap</gi>, Enveloppe d’objet binaires <gi>objectBinWrap</gi>, Date <gi>date</gi>, Intervalle de dates <gi>dateRange</gi>, Ensemble de dates
                        <gi>dateSet</gi>, Forme du nom de lieu <gi>placeEntry</gi> et Note descriptive <gi>descriptiveNote</gi>. Chacune des relations spécifiques contient des attributs facultatifs en fonction du type de la relation
                     décrite. Ils contiennent :</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>cpfRelation</gi> -Relation avec une collectivité, une personne ou une famille. Contient un attribut <att>cpfRelationType</att>. Les valeurs sont : "identity" (identitaire), "hierarchical" (hiérarchique),
                     "hierarchical-parent" (hiérarchique-parent), "hierarchical-child" (hiérarchique-enfant), "temporal" (chronologique), "temporal-earlier" (chronologique-prédécesseur), "temporal-later" (chronologique-successeur), "family"
                     (familiale), "associative" (d’association).</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>functionRelation</gi> - Relation avec une fonction. Contient un attribut <att>functionRelationType</att>. Les valeurs sont : "controls" (contrôle), "owns" (est titulaire de), "performs" (exerce).</p>
                  <p>
                     <gi>resourceRelation</gi> - Relation avec une ressource. Contient un attribut <att>ressourceRelationType</att>. Les valeurs sont : creatorOf (producteur de), subjectOf (sujet de), other (autre). </p>
                  <p>Il existe d’autres attributs disponibles pour les éléments d’encodage des relations qui sont <att>lastDateTimeVerified</att> ainsi que la suite des attributs simples XLink.</p>
                  <p>Deux arguments logiques étayent le fait d’avoir établi une liste fermée de valeurs pour typer les relations. Premièrement, il est dans l’intérêt général d’exprimer de manière cohérente des relations et la navigation
                     entre ces relations, de même que la réalisation d’affichages graphiques d’organigrammes, d’arbres généalogiques de familles et de frises chronologiques. Cette liste fermée de types de relations représente une tentative
                     expérimentale pour fournir les données nécessaires à la construction de ces affichages. Sur ce point, il n’y a pas eu de tests d’affichages graphiques pour prouver l’utilité des structures. Deuxièmement, il est
                     nécessaire de donner des informations simples sur la nature des relations afin de les rendre intelligibles aux utilisateurs. Étant donné les différences culturelles et institutionnelles, les types possibles de relations
                     sont, en principe, en nombre illimité. Toutefois, les concepteurs de l’EAC-CPF ont décidé qu’un consensus était nécessaire sur un ensemble restreint de types de relations pour atteindre un niveau minimum de
                     fonctionnalité.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>XLink</head>
                  <p>Le schéma EAC-CPF permet d’établir des liens vers des ressources externes, en utilisant un sous-ensemble limité du standard XLink, défini à http://www.w3.org/TR/xlink/. Les attributs XLink peuvent être utilisés pour
                     créer et décrire les liens entre les ressources. Ils sont en particulier employés pour référencer un ensemble de relations plus riche que celles exprimées par <att>cpfRelationType</att>, <att>functionRelationType</att>,
                     et <att>resourceRelationtype</att>. Les attributs XLink sont disponibles dans les éléments suivants : Citation <gi>citation</gi>, Relation avec une collectivité, une personne ou une famille <gi>cpfRelation</gi>,
                     Relation avec une fonction <gi>functionRelation</gi>, Relation avec une ressource <gi>resourceRelation</gi>, Composant d’un ensemble <gi>setComponent</gi>, et Source <gi>source</gi>.</p>
                  <p>On trouvera dans la partie du dictionnaire des balises consacrée aux attributs une description plus complète de ces attributs. Les informations ci-dessous donnent une idée synthétique de leur utilisation les uns par
                     rapport aux autres.</p>
                  <p>L’attribut de typage de lien</p>
                  <p>
                     <att>xlink:type</att> - Cet attribut est requis chaque fois qu’un autre attribut XLink est utilisé avec l’élément parent. Il prend la valeur fixe “simple” depuis que l’implémentation de XLink prévue par l’EAC-CPF ne
                     supporte que les liens vers l’extérieur avec une ressource. Si plusieurs liens vers l’extérieur sont requis, chaque lien doit être représenté dans un nouvel élément parent.</p>
                  <p>L’attribut de localisation</p>
                  <p>
                     <att>xlink:href</att> - Cet attribut facultatif peut être utilisé pour donner la localisation de la ressource liée. Le lien doit être un URI valide.</p>
                  <p>Attributs sémantiques</p>
                  <p>
                     <att>xlink:arcrole</att> - Cet attribut peut être utilisé dans les éléments Relation avec une collectivité, une personne ou une famille <gi>cpfRelation</gi>, Relation avec une fonction <gi>functionRelation</gi>,
                     Relation avec une ressource <gi>resourceRelation</gi> pour fournir une description plus précise de la relation entre l’entité décrite dans l’instance EAC-CPF et la ressource à laquelle elle est liée. Lorsqu’il est
                     utilisé dans les éléments Citation <gi>citation</gi>, Composant d’un ensemble <gi>setComponent</gi>, et Source <gi>source</gi>, il fournit une description explicite, voire plus précise de la relation que celle supposée
                     par le contexte de l’utilisation. La valeur doit être un URI valide.</p>
                  <p>
                     <att>xlink:role</att> - Cet attribut facultatif est utilisé pour fournir une indication sur la nature de la ressource distante liée. En particulier, il permet de préciser la nature de la ressource liée dans l’élément
                     Relation avec une ressource <gi>resourceRelation</gi>, telle qu’elle est décrite dans l’élément 6.2 « Nature des ressources associées » d’ISAAR (CPF). La valeur fournie doit être un URI valide.</p>
                  <p>Attributs donnant des instructions sur le fonctionnement technique des liens</p>
                  <p>
                     <att>xlink:actuate</att> - Cet attribut facultatif peut être utilisé conjointement avec xlink:show pour donner des instructions à une application externe sur les modalités de résolution du lien vers une ressource
                     extérieure. Par exemple, une application peut recevoir comme instruction de charger la ressource lorsque le document XML parent est chargé ou seulement lorsque la page est demandée par un utilisateur ou une
                     application.</p>
                  <p>
                     <att>xlink:show</att> - Cet attribut facultatif peut être utilisé conjointement avec xlink:actuate pour donner des instructions à une application externe sur la manière de présenter à l’utilisateur la ressource liée,
                     lorsque le lien vers celle-ci est résolu. Par exemple, l’application peut recevoir comme instruction de remplacer le document XML lors du chargement, ou de le charger dans une nouvelle fenêtre ou dans un nouvel
                     onglet.</p>
                  <p>
                     <att>xlink:title</att> - Cet attribut facultatif peut être utilisé pour fournir une légende ou un titre pouvant être utilisé par un système ou une application externe lors de l’affichage du lien sur une interface
                     publique.</p>
                  <p>Les navigateurs Mozilla, tels que Firefox, sont les seules applications « utilisateurs standards » qui incluent du support natif pour une gamme limitée d’attributs XLlink. Par conséquent les utilisateurs désireux
                     d’implémenter l’EAC-CPF devront envisager une implémentation complète des attributs XLink en utilisant les instructions côté serveur. Un exemple d’implémentation démontrant les effets attendus de l’usage de XLink est
                     fourni à l’adresse http://www.snee.com/xml/xlink/sxlinkdemo.xml.</p>
                  <p>Voici un exemple montrant comment XLink peut être implémenté en s’appuyant sur un vocabulaire externe pour indiquer que l’information contenue dans l’URL lié décrit l’épouse de la personne qui fait l’objet de la
                     description dans l’instance EAC-CPF.</p>
                  <eg:egXML>
                     <eac-cpf:cpfRelation cpfRelationType="family" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:arcrole="http://library.illinois.edu/archives/eac- cpfRelations.html#spouseOf"
                        xlink:href="http://library.illinois.edu/archives/archon/ index.php?p=creators/creator&amp;id=546" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple">
                        <eac-cpf:relationEntry> Gregory, John Milton </eac-cpf:relationEntry>
                        <eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                           <eac-cpf:p> John Milton Gregory was the husband of Louisa Allen Gregory. </eac-cpf:p>
                        </eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                     </eac-cpf:cpfRelation>
                     <eac-cpf:resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:role="http://library.illinois.edu/archives/eac- cpfRelations.html#collector" xlink:type="simple">
                        <eac-cpf:relationEntry> Collezione Fortunato Depero (Polo culturale e Galleria Museum Depero, Roverto </eac-cpf:relationEntry>
                        <eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                           <eac-cpf:p> ITA MART, Collezione Depero, Collezione d'arte, 1919-1959, Creatore della collezione </eac-cpf:p>
                        </eac-cpf:descriptiveNote>
                     </eac-cpf:resourceRelation>
                  </eg:egXML>
                  <p/>
                  <p>Le vocabulaire référencé ci-dessus sur purl.org n’a pas vocation à être normatif, il est fourni seulement à titre d’illustration. Il est souhaitable qu’à l’avenir, les communautés professionnelles développent et gèrent
                     des vocabulaires contrôlés pour décrire la nature des relations avec les personnes, familles, collectivités, ressources et fonctions qui sont décrites dans les éléments Relation avec une collectivité, une personne ou
                     une famille <gi>cpfRelation</gi>, Relation avec une fonction <gi>functionRelation</gi>, Relation avec une ressource <gi>resourceRelation</gi>. De tels vocabulaires peuvent être gérés au niveau local, national ou même
                     international, probablement en continuation du travail du Groupe de travail EAC.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>
                     <att>localType</att>
                  </head>
                  <p>L’EAC-CPF ayant été élaboré par un travail mené à l’échelle internationale, ses concepteurs se sont efforcés de trouver un accord afin de s’adapter aux différences culturelles et institutionnelles. La sémantique et la
                     structure décrites ci-dessus respectent le consensus actuel et sont étroitement liées à ISAAR (CPF).</p>
                  <p>En plus de l’élément Description locale <gi>localDescription</gi>, ci-dessus décrit, plusieurs éléments de l’EAC-CPF peuvent également être qualifiés par l’attribut <att>localType</att>. Cet attribut permet à l’EAC-CPF
                     de s’adapter aux environnements nationaux, régionaux et locaux qui nécessitent des sémantiques plus spécifiques que celles fournies par l’EAC-CPF, ou des catégories descriptives non traitées par l’EAC-CPF.</p>
                  <!--FC Éléments-->
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="elements">
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-abbreviation.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-abstract.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-address.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-addressLine.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-agencyCode.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-agencyName.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-agent.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-agentType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-alternativeForm.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-alternativeSet.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-authorizedForm.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-biogHist.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-chronItem.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-chronList.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-citation.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-componentEntry.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-control.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-conventionDeclaration.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-cpfDescription.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-cpfRelation.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-date.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-dateRange.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-dateSet.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-description.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-descriptiveNote.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-eac-cpf.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-entityId.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-entityType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-event.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-eventDateTime.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-eventDesccription.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-eventType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-existDates.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-fromDate.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-function.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-functionRelation.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-functions.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-generalContext.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-identity.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-item.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-language.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-languageDeclaration.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-languagesUsed.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-languageUsed.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-legalStatus.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-legalStatuses.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-level.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-list.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-localControl.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-localDescription.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-localDescriptions.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-localTypeDeclaration.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-maintenanceAgency.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-maintenanceEvent.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-maintenanceHistory.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-maintenanceStatus.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-mandate.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-mandates.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-multipleIdentities.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-nameEntry.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-nameEntryParallel.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-objectBinWrap.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-objectXMLWrap.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-occupation.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-occupations.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-otherAgencyCode.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-otherRecordId.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-outline.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-p.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-part.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-place.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-placeEntry.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-placeRole.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-places.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-preferredForm.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-publicationStatus.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-recordId.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-relationEntry.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-relations.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-resourceRelation.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-script.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-setComponent.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-source.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-sourceEntry.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-sources.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-span.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-structureOrGenealogy.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-term.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-toDate.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/elem-useDates.xml" parse="xml"/>
         </div>
         <div type="attributes">
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-accuracy.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-altitude.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-countryCode.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-cpfRelationType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-functionRelationType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-identityType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-languageCode.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-lastDateTimeVerified.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-latitude.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-localType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-longitude.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-notAfter.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-notBefore.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-resourceRelationType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-scriptCode.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-standardDate.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-standardDateTime.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-style.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-transliteration.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-vocabularySource.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xlinkActuate.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xlinkArcrole.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xlinkHref.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xlinkRole.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xlinkShow.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xlinkTitle.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xlinkType.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xmlbase.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xmlid.xml" parse="xml"/>
            <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="./descriptions-multilingual/attr-xmllang.xml" parse="xml"/>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div xml:id="appendix-eng" type="appendix" xml:lang="eng">
            <head>ISAAR(CPF) Crosswalk</head>
            <list>
               <label>ISAAR (CPF)</label>
               <item>EAC-CPF</item>
               <label>5.1 Identity area</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>identity</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.1.1 Type of entity</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>entityType</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.1.2 Authorized form(s) of name</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>nameEntry</gi> or <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> with <gi>authorizedForm</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.1.3 Parallel forms of name</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.1.4 Standardized forms of name according to other rules</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>nameEntry</gi> or <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> with <gi>authorizedForm</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.1.5 Other forms of name</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>nameEntry</gi> or <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> with <gi>alternativeForm</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.1.6 Identifiers for corporate bodies</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>entityId</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2 Description area</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>description</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.1 Dates of existence</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>existDates</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.2 History</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>biogHist</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.3 Places</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>place</gi> or <gi>places</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.4 Legal status</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>legalStatus</gi> or <gi>legalStatuses</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.5 Functions, occupations and activities</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>function</gi> or <gi>functions</gi>, <gi>occupation</gi> or <gi>occupations</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.6 Mandates/Sources of authority</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>mandate</gi> or <gi>mandates</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.7 Internal structures/Genealogy</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.2.8 General context</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>generalContext</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.3 Relationships area</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>relations</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.3.1 Names/Identifiers of related corporate bodies, persons or families</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>cpfRelation</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.3.2 Category of relationship</label>
               <item><!--FC   <gi>cpfRelation cpfRelationType="[value]"</gi>--><tag>cpfRelation cpfRelationType="[value]"</tag>
               </item>
               <label>5.3.3 Description of relationship</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>objectXMLWrap</gi> or <gi>objectBinWrap</gi> or <gi>relationEntry</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.3.4 Dates of the relationship</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>cpfRelation</gi>/<gi>date</gi> or <gi>dateRange</gi> or <gi>dateSet</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4 Control area</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>control</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.1 Authority record identifier</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>recordId</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.2 Institution identifiers</label>
               <item><!-- <gi>maintenanceAgency/agencyCode and/or agencyName</gi>--><gi>maintenanceAgency</gi>/<gi>agencyCode</gi> and/or <gi>agencyName</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.3 Rules and/or conventions</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>conventionDeclaration</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.4 Status</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>maintenanceStatus</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.5 Level of detail</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>localControl</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.6 Dates of creation, revision or deletion</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>maintenanceEvent</gi>/<gi>eventDateTime</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.7 Languages and scripts</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>languageDeclaration</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.8 Sources</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>sources</gi>
               </item>
               <label>5.4.9 Maintenance notes</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>maintenanceEvent</gi>/<gi>maintenanceDescription</gi>
               </item>
               <label>6. Relating corporate bodies, persons, and families to archival materials and other resources</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>resourceRelation</gi>
               </item>
               <label>6.1 Identifiers and titles of related resources</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>objectXMLWrap</gi> or <gi>objectBinWrap</gi> or <gi>relationEntry</gi>
               </item>
               <label>6.2 Types of related resources</label>
               <item><!--  FC  <gi>resourceRelation xlink:role="[value]"</gi>--><tag>resourceRelation xlink:role="[value]"</tag>
               </item>
               <label>6.3 Nature of relationships</label>
               <item><!-- FC <gi>resourceRelation resourceRelationType="[value]"</gi>--><tag>resourceRelation resourceRelationType="[value]"</tag>
               </item>
               <label>6.4 Dates of related resources and/or relationships</label>
               <item>
                  <gi>resourceRelation</gi>/<gi>date</gi> or <gi>dateRange</gi> or <gi>dateSet</gi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div xml:id="appendix-fre" type="appendix" xml:lang="fre">
            <head>Correspondance ISAAR(CPF) – EAC-CPF</head>
            <table>
               <row>
                  <cell>ISAAR (CPF)</cell>
                  <cell>EAC-CPF</cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.1 Zone d’identification</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>identity</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.1.1 Type d’entité</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>entityType</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.1.2 Forme(s) autorisée(s) du nom</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>nameEntry</gi> ou <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> avec <gi>authorizedForm</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.1.3 Formes parallèles du nom </cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.1.4 Formes du nom normalisées selon d’autres conventions</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>nameEntry</gi> ou <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> avec <gi>authorizedForm</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.1.5 Autres formes du nom</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>nameEntry</gi> ou <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> avec <gi>alternativeForm</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.1.6 Numéro d’immatriculation des collectivités</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>entityId</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2 Zone de la description</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>description</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.1 Dates d’existence</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>existDates</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.2 Histoire</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>biogHist</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.3 Lieux</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>place</gi> ou <gi>places</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.4 Statut juridique</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>legalStatus</gi> avec <gi>legalStatuses</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.5 Fonctions et activités</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>function</gi> ou <gi>functions</gi>, <gi>occupation</gi> ou <gi>occupations</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.6 Textes de référence</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>mandate</gi> ou <gi>mandates</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.7 Organisation interne/généalogie</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>structureOrGenealogy</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.2.8 Contexte général</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>generalContext</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.3 Zone des relations</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>relations</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.3.1 Nom(s)/Numéro d’immatriculation des collectivités, des personnes ou des familles associées</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>cpfRelation</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.3.2 Type de relation</cell>
                  <cell><!--FC &lt;cpfRelation cpfRelationType="[value]"&gt;--><tag>cpfRelation cpfRelationType="[value]"</tag>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.3.3 Description de la relation</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>objectXMLWrap</gi> ou <gi>objectBinWrap</gi> ou <gi>relationEntry</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.3.4 Dates de la relation</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>cpfRelation</gi>/<gi>date</gi> ou <gi>dateRange</gi> ou <gi>dateSet</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4 Zone du contrôle</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>control</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.1 Code d’identification de la notice d’autorité</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>recordId</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.2 Code(s) d’identification du ou des service(s)</cell>
                  <cell><!--FC &lt;maintenanceAgency&gt;--><gi>maintenanceAgency</gi>/<gi>agencyCode</gi> et/ou <gi>agencyName</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.3 Règles ou conventions</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>conventionDeclaration</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.4 Niveau d’élaboration</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>maintenanceStatus</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.5 Niveau de détail</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>localControl</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.6 Dates de création, de révision ou de destruction</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>maintenanceEvent</gi>/<gi>eventDateTime</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.7 Langue(s) et écriture(s)</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>languageDeclaration</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.8 Sources</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>sources</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>5.4.9 Notes relatives à la mise à jour de la notice</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>maintenanceEvent</gi>/<gi>maintenanceDescription</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>6. Relations entre les collectivités, les personnes et les familles et des ressources archivistiques ou autres </cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>resourceRelation</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>6.1 Identifiants et intitulés des ressources associées</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>objectXMLWrap</gi> ou <gi>objectBinWrap</gi> ou <gi>relationEntry</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>6.2 Nature des resources associées</cell>
                  <cell><!--FC &lt;resourceRelation xlink:role="[value]"&gt;--><tag>resourceRelation xlink:role="[value]"</tag>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>6.3 Nature des relations</cell>
                  <cell><!--FC &lt;resourceRelation resourceRelationType="[value]"&gt;--><tag>resourceRelation resourceRelationType="[value]"</tag>
                  </cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell>6.4 Dates des ressources associées et/ou des relations</cell>
                  <cell>
                     <gi>resourceRelation</gi>/<gi>date</gi> ou <gi>dateRange</gi> ou <gi>dateSet</gi>
                  </cell>
               </row>
            </table>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
