<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="xmllang"
     type="attributeDocumentation">
   <head>
      <att>xml:lang</att>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">XML Language</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">Three-letter ISO 639-2 language code.</p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">Code de langue à trois lettres ISO 639-2.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>The <att>xml:lang</att> may occur on any element intended to contain
							natural language content whenever information about the language of the content of this
							element and its children are needed. <att>xml:lang</att> should be used when the language of
							the element differs from the Language Code declared in the <att>languageCode</att> attribute
							on the element <gi>language</gi> in the control section. The values in the list are taken
							from ISO 639-2 Codes for the Representation of Names of Languages. The list can be downloaded
							from the website of the Library of Congress which is the registration agency of the standard
								(http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/langhome.html).</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="fre">
      <p>L’attribut <att>xml:lang</att> s’applique à tout élément dont le contenu est rédigé en langage naturel, chaque fois qu’il est nécessaire d’indiquer la langue du contenu de cet élément et de ses enfants. On doit utiliser
                     l’attribut <att>xml:lang</att> quand la langue de l’élément diffère de celle déclarée dans l’attribut <att>languageCode</att> de l’élément Langue <gi>language</gi> qui fait partie du contrôle de la description. Les
                     valeurs de la liste sont issues de la norme ISO 639-2 Codes pour la représentation des noms de langue. On peut télécharger cette liste à partir du site de la Bibliothèque du Congrès qui est l’agence d’enregistrement de
                     la norme (http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/langhome.html).</p>
      <p/>
      <p/>
      <p/>
   </div>
   <div type="datatype" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>IS0 639-2 Codes for the Representation of Names of Languages.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="datatype" xml:lang="fre">
      <p>languageVoir ISO 639-2 Codes pour la représentation des noms de langue</p>
   </div>
</div>