<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="identity"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>identity</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">Identity</p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">Identity</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">A wrapper element for the name portion of the EAC-CPF instance.</p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">Élément englobant pour les formes du nom de l’instance EAC-CPF.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>
         <gi>identity</gi> is a container element grouping all the necessary elements to the name
								identification of the EAC-CPF instance. Within this element the <gi>entityType</gi>
								element is required and specifies the type of entity being described (i.e., corporateBody,
								family, or person), and one or more <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements and / or one or more
									<gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> elements specifying names by which the entity is known. An
								optional <gi>entityId</gi> is available for any identifiers associated with the
								entity.</p>
      <p>All the names by which the entity being described in the EAC-CPF instance is known are
								provided within this element. Within <gi>identity</gi>, the names of the entity, whether
								authorized or alternatives, should be recorded in a <gi>nameEntry</gi> element. If there
								is more than one name for the entity, each of them should be recorded in a separate
									<gi>nameEntry</gi> element.</p>
      <p>In addition to needing to accommodate one or more names used for or by the entity,
									<gi>identity</gi> may accommodate two or more parallel names in different languages or
								scripts. In countries where there is more than one official language, such as Canada or
								Switzerland, names of entities are frequently provided in more than one language. Within
									<gi>identity</gi>, a <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> element should be used to group two or
								more <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements that represent parallel forms of the name of the entity
								being described.</p>
      <p>Within <gi>identity</gi>, a <gi>descriptiveNote</gi> element may be used to record
								other information in a textual form that assists in the identification of the entity.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="fre">
      <p>Identité <gi>identity</gi> est un élément englobant qui regroupe l’ensemble des éléments nécessaires à l’identification du nom de l’instance EAC-CPF.</p>
      <p>À l’intérieur de cet élément sont obligatoires l’élément Type d’entité <gi>entityType</gi>, qui indique le type de l’entité décrite (collectivité, famille ou personne), et au moins un élément Forme du nom
                        <gi>nameEntry</gi>, qui spécifie les noms sous lesquels l’entité est connue. Un élément facultatif Identifiant de l’entité <gi>entityId</gi> est utilisé pour indiquer tous les identifiants relatifs à l’entité.</p>
      <p>L’ensemble des noms sous lesquels est connue l’entité décrite dans l’instance EAC-CPF sont mentionnés dans cet élément. Dans <gi>identity</gi>, les noms de l’entité, qu’ils soient formes retenues ou formes rejetées,
                     doivent figurer dans un élément <gi>nameEntry</gi> particulier.</p>
      <p>En plus de contenir un ou plusieurs nom(s) utilisé(s) par ou pour une entité, <gi>identity</gi> peut inclure au moins deux formes parallèles en différentes langues ou écritures. Dans les pays qui ont plus d’une langue
                     officielle, à l’exemple du Canada ou de la Suisse, les noms des entités se trouvent fréquemment dans plusieurs langues.</p>
      <p>Dans <gi>identity</gi>, un élément Forme parallèle du nom <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> doit être utilisé pour regrouper au moins deux éléments <gi>nameEntry</gi> qui expriment des formes parallèles du nom de l’entité
                     décrite. <gi>identity</gi> contient un élément Note descriptive <gi>descriptiveNote</gi> qui peut être utilisé pour entrer sous forme textuelle toute autre information aidant à l'identification de l’entité.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>descriptiveNote, entityId, entityType, nameEntry,
							nameEntryParallel</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>cpfDescription</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>identityType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:base</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>identityType</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
            <label>xml:base</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.1</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>1</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:identity xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:entityId>CLU-SC-000008</eac-cpf:entityId>
            <eac-cpf:entityType>person</eac-cpf:entityType>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry>
               <eac-cpf:part>Brown, Bob</eac-cpf:part>
               <eac-cpf:useDates>
                  <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                     <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1886">1886</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                     <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1959">1959</eac-cpf:toDate>
                  </eac-cpf:dateRange>
               </eac-cpf:useDates>
               <eac-cpf:authorizedForm>AACR2</eac-cpf:authorizedForm>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry>
               <eac-cpf:part>Brown, Robert Carlton</eac-cpf:part>
               <eac-cpf:useDates>
                  <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                     <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1886">1886</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                     <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1959">1959</eac-cpf:toDate>
                  </eac-cpf:dateRange>
               </eac-cpf:useDates>
               <eac-cpf:alternativeForm>AACR2</eac-cpf:alternativeForm>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
         </eac-cpf:identity>
      </egXML>
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <identity>
            <entityId> CLU-SC-000008 </entityId>
            <entityType> person </entityType>
            <nameEntry>
               <part> Brown, Bob </part>
               <useDates>
                  <dateRange>
                     <fromDate standardDate="1886"> 1886 </fromDate>
                     <toDate standardDate="1959"> 1959 </toDate>
                  </dateRange>
               </useDates>
               <authorizedForm> AACR2 </authorizedForm>
            </nameEntry>
            <nameEntry>
               <part> Brown, Robert Carlton </part>
               <useDates>
                  <dateRange>
                     <fromDate standardDate="1886"> 1886 </fromDate>
                     <toDate standardDate="1959"> 1959 </toDate>
                  </dateRange>
               </useDates>
               <alternativeForm> AACR2 </alternativeForm>
            </nameEntry>
         </identity>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>