<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="preferredForm"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>preferredForm</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">Preferred Form of Name</p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">Forme préférée</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">An element used to indicate which of the parallel names recorded within
								<gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, is the preferred one for display purposes in a given
							context.</p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">Élément employé pour indiquer parmi les formes parallèles du nom encodées dans <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> celle qui est forme préférée dans un contexte donné.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>In cases where parallel names are encoded as multiple <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements within
									<gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, a <gi>nameEntry</gi> may be chosen as preferred in a given
								context. The <gi>preferredForm</gi> element is used only when <gi>nameEntry</gi> occurs
								within <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>. It is used only to distinguish the preferred form of
								the name to be displayed, as compared to the other authorized parallel names recorded in
								other <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements.</p>
      <p>The <gi>preferredForm</gi> element contains an abbreviation of the relevant national,
								international or other convention or rule applied by a given agency and according to which
								the name thus qualified is deemed as preferred to the others. The abbreviations expressed in
									<gi>preferredForm</gi> must be declared within the <gi>conventionDeclaration</gi>
								element in <gi>control</gi>.</p>
      <p>Within <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, <gi>preferredForm</gi> may occur simultaneously
								with <gi>authorizedForm</gi> elements. While the <gi>authorizedForm</gi>, when used
								within <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, qualifies collectively the set of the parallel forms
								recorded in the separate <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements, the <gi>preferredForm</gi> element
								is used specifically within the <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements to qualify the preferred
								form(s) of the name that an agency chooses to display.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="fre">
      <p>Lorsque des formes parallèles du nom sont encodées dans plusieurs éléments Forme du nom <gi>nameEntry</gi> comme sous-éléments de Formes parallèles du nom <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, un élément Forme du nom
                        <gi>nameEntry</gi> peut être choisi comme forme préférée du nom dans un contexte donné. L’élément Forme préférée <gi>preferredForm</gi> est employé seulement quand <gi>nameEntry</gi> est un sous-élément de
                        <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>. Il est utilisé uniquement pour distinguer la forme préférée du nom des autres formes autorisées parallèles du nom encodées dans d’autres éléments <gi>nameEntry</gi>. </p>
      <p>Le contenu de l’élément Forme préférée <gi>preferredForm</gi> est une abréviation de la règle ou convention nationale, internationale ou d’une autre norme appropriée utilisée par une agence donnée qui définit comme
                     préférée la forme du nom ainsi spécifiée, à la différence des autres formes. Les abréviations indiquées dans Forme autorisée <gi>authorizedForm</gi> doivent être précisées dans le sous-élément
                        <gi>conventionDeclaration</gi> de <gi>control</gi>. </p>
      <p>Dans l’élément Formes parallèles du nom <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, <gi>preferredForm</gi> peut être utilisé aux côtés d’éléments Forme autorisée <gi>authorizedForm</gi>. Lorsque l’élément <gi>authorizedForm</gi>,
                     utilisé comme élément enfant de <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi>, qualifie collectivement l’ensemble des formes parallèles encodées dans des éléments <gi>nameEntry</gi> distincts, l’élément <gi>preferredForm</gi> est employé
                     spécifiquement pour qualifier la ou les forme(s) préférée(s) du nom choisie(s) comme telle(s) par l’agence.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>NMTOKEN</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>nameEntry (only when it occurs within nameEntryParallel)</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.1.3</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>0...∞</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:nameEntryParallel xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry xml:lang="fre" scriptCode="Latn">
               <eac-cpf:part>Institut international des droits de l'homme</eac-cpf:part>
               <eac-cpf:preferredForm>AFNOR_Z44-060</eac-cpf:preferredForm>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry xml:lang="eng" scriptCode="Latn">International institute of human
										rights</eac-cpf:nameEntry>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry xml:lang="spa" scriptCode="Latn">
               <eac-cpf:part>Instituto internacional de derechos humanos</eac-cpf:part>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
            <eac-cpf:authorizedForm>AFNOR_Z44-060</eac-cpf:authorizedForm>
         </eac-cpf:nameEntryParallel>
      </egXML>
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <nameEntryParallel>
            <nameEntry xml:lang="fre" scriptCode="Latn">
               <part> Institut international des droits de l'homme </part>
               <preferredForm> AFNOR_Z44-060 </preferredForm>
            </nameEntry>
            <nameEntry xml:lang="eng" scriptCode="Latn"> International institute of human rights </nameEntry>
            <nameEntry xml:lang="spa" scriptCode="Latn">
               <part> Instituto internacional de derechos humanos </part>
            </nameEntry>
            <authorizedForm> AFNOR_Z44-060 </authorizedForm>
         </nameEntryParallel>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>