<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="description"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>description</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="eng">Description</p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">Description</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="eng">A wrapper for all of the content elements comprising description (as
							specified in the ISAAR (CPF) Description Area) of the entity described in the EAC-CPF
							instance.</p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">Élément englobant pour tous les éléments de contenu comprenant la description (conforme à la zone de la description dans ISAAR(CPF)) de l’entité décrite dans l’instance EAC-CPF.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="eng">
      <p>The elements that constitute <gi>description</gi> together permit descriptive
								information to be encoded in either structured or unstructured fashions, or in a combined
								approach. <gi>description</gi> accommodates encoding all of the data elements that
								comprise the Description Area of ISAAR (CPF) including historical, biographical, and
								genealogical information; legal status and mandates; functions, occupations, and activities,
								and the dates and places that further constrain those elements.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description" xml:lang="fre">
      <p>Les éléments constitutifs de la Description <gi>description</gi> permettent d’encoder des informations descriptives de manière structurée ou non, ou dans une approche combinant les deux méthodes. L’élément
                        <gi>description</gi> accueille l’encodage de tous les éléments de données compris dans la zone de la description d’ISAAR(CPF), parmi lesquels les informations historiques, biographiques et généalogiques, le statut
                     juridique et les textes de référence, les fonctions, tâches et activités, ainsi que les dates et les lieux qui viennent préciser ces éléments.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>biogHist, existDates, function, functions, generalContext, languageUsed,
							languagesUsed, legalStatus, legalStatuses, localDescription, localDescriptions, mandate,
							mandates, occupation, occupations, place, places, structureOrGenealogy</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>cpfDescription</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="eng">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>xml:base</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      <p xml:lang="fre">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>xml:base</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Facultatif</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.2</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>0...1</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <eac-cpf:description xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:existDates>
               <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                  <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1765-09-18">September 18, 1765</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                  <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1846-06-01">June 1, 1846</eac-cpf:toDate>
               </eac-cpf:dateRange>
            </eac-cpf:existDates>
            <eac-cpf:place>
               <eac-cpf:placeEntry altitude="389" latitude="46.140833" longitude="12.215556">Belluno</eac-cpf:placeEntry>
               <eac-cpf:placeRole>Birthplace</eac-cpf:placeRole>
               <eac-cpf:date standardDate="1765-09-18">September 18, 1765</eac-cpf:date>
            </eac-cpf:place>
            <eac-cpf:biogHist>
               <eac-cpf:p>Cappellari was born at Belluno on 18 September 1765 to a noble family. At an
											early age he joined the order of the Camaldolese (part of the Benedictine monastic
											family) and entered the Monastery of San Michele di Murano, near Venice. As a Camaldolese
											monk, Cappellari rapidly gained distinction for his theological and linguistic skills.
											His first appearance before a wider public was in 1799, when he published against the
											Italian Jansenists a controversial work entitled <eac-cpf:span localType="title" style="font-style:italic">II Trionfo della Santa Sede</eac-cpf:span>, which besides
											passing through several editions in Italy, has been translated into several European
											languages. In 1800, he became a member of the Academy of the Catholic Religion, founded
											by Pope Pius VII (1800-1823), to which he contributed a number of memoirs on theological
											and philosophical questions, and in 1805 was made abbot of San Gregorio on the Caelian
											Hill.</eac-cpf:p>
            </eac-cpf:biogHist>
         </eac-cpf:description>
      </egXML>
      <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
         <description>
            <existDates>
               <dateRange>
                  <fromDate standardDate="1765-09-18"> September 18, 1765 </fromDate>
                  <toDate standardDate="1846-06-01"> June 1, 1846 </toDate>
               </dateRange>
            </existDates>
            <place>
               <placeEntry altitude="389" latitude="46.140833" longitude="12.215556"> Belluno </placeEntry>
               <placeRole> Birthplace </placeRole>
               <date standardDate="1765-09-18"> September 18, 1765 </date>
            </place>
            <biogHist>
               <p> Cappellari was born at Belluno on 18 September 1765 to a noble family. At an early age he joined the order of the Camaldolese (part of the Benedictine monastic family) and entered the Monastery of San Michele
                              di Murano, near Venice. As a Camaldolese monk, Cappellari rapidly gained distinction for his theological and linguistic skills. His first appearance before a wider public was in 1799, when he published against
                              the Italian Jansenists a controversial work entitled <span localType="title" style="font-style:italic"> II Trionfo della Santa Sede </span> , which besides passing through several editions in Italy, has been
                              translated into several European languages. In 1800, he became a member of the Academy of the Catholic Religion, founded by Pope Pius VII (1800-1823), to which he contributed a number of memoirs on theological
                              and philosophical questions, and in 1805 was made abbot of San Gregorio on the Caelian Hill. </p>
            </biogHist>
         </description>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>