<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="maintenanceStatus">
   <head>
      <gi>maintenanceStatus</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="en">Maintenance Status</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="en">The current drafting status of the EAC-CPF instance.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description">
      <p xml:lang="en">A required element within <gi>control</gi> that records the current drafting status of
								an EAC-CPF instance: as an EAC-CPF instance is modified or other events happen to it (as
								recorded in the <gi>maintenanceHistory</gi> element), the maintenance status should also
								be amended to reflect the current drafting status.</p>
      <p xml:lang="en">On first creation the status would be "new", which on revision can be changed to
								"revised". Because it is important to be clear what has happened to records particularly
								when sharing and making links between them, a number of status values are available for
								records that are no longer current. A record that is simply deleted from a system can be
								given the status "deleted", but in cases where a record is marked as not current (obsolete
								or rejected) but kept for reference then it should be given the status "cancelled". If a
								record is deleted though because it has become superseded by two or more records then its
								status should be given as "deletedSplit", while if it has simply been replaced by a new
								record then "deletedReplaced" is the appropriate status value. A "derived" status value is
								available to indicate that the record was derived from another descriptive system.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>"cancelled" or "deleted" or "deletedReplaced" or "deletedSplit" or
							"derived" or "new" or "revised"</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>control</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="en">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.4.4</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>1</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML>
         <eac-cpf:maintenanceStatus xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">new</eac-cpf:maintenanceStatus>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>