<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="identity">
   <head>
      <gi>identity</gi>
   </head>
   <div type="fullName">
      <p xml:lang="en">Identity</p>
   </div>
   <div type="summary">
      <p xml:lang="en">A wrapper element for the name portion of the EAC-CPF instance.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="description">
      <p xml:lang="en">
         <gi>identity</gi> is a container element grouping all the necessary elements to the name
								identification of the EAC-CPF instance. Within this element the <gi>entityType</gi>
								element is required and specifies the type of entity being described (i.e., corporateBody,
								family, or person), and one or more <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements and / or one or more
									<gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> elements specifying names by which the entity is known. An
								optional <gi>entityId</gi> is available for any identifiers associated with the
								entity.</p>
      <p xml:lang="en">All the names by which the entity being described in the EAC-CPF instance is known are
								provided within this element. Within <gi>identity</gi>, the names of the entity, whether
								authorized or alternatives, should be recorded in a <gi>nameEntry</gi> element. If there
								is more than one name for the entity, each of them should be recorded in a separate
									<gi>nameEntry</gi> element.</p>
      <p xml:lang="en">In addition to needing to accommodate one or more names used for or by the entity,
									<gi>identity</gi> may accommodate two or more parallel names in different languages or
								scripts. In countries where there is more than one official language, such as Canada or
								Switzerland, names of entities are frequently provided in more than one language. Within
									<gi>identity</gi>, a <gi>nameEntryParallel</gi> element should be used to group two or
								more <gi>nameEntry</gi> elements that represent parallel forms of the name of the entity
								being described.</p>
      <p xml:lang="en">Within <gi>identity</gi>, a <gi>descriptiveNote</gi> element may be used to record
								other information in a textual form that assists in the identification of the entity.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>descriptiveNote, entityId, entityType, nameEntry,
							nameEntryParallel</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>cpfDescription</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <p xml:lang="en">
         <list type="gloss">
            <label>identityType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>localType</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:base</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:id</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>xml:lang</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="reference">
      <p>ISAAR (CPF) 5.1</p>
   </div>
   <div type="occurrence">
      <p>1</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <egXML>
         <eac-cpf:identity xmlns:eac-cpf="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4">
            <eac-cpf:entityId>CLU-SC-000008</eac-cpf:entityId>
            <eac-cpf:entityType>person</eac-cpf:entityType>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry>
               <eac-cpf:part>Brown, Bob</eac-cpf:part>
               <eac-cpf:useDates>
                  <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                     <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1886">1886</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                     <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1959">1959</eac-cpf:toDate>
                  </eac-cpf:dateRange>
               </eac-cpf:useDates>
               <eac-cpf:authorizedForm>AACR2</eac-cpf:authorizedForm>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
            <eac-cpf:nameEntry>
               <eac-cpf:part>Brown, Robert Carlton</eac-cpf:part>
               <eac-cpf:useDates>
                  <eac-cpf:dateRange>
                     <eac-cpf:fromDate standardDate="1886">1886</eac-cpf:fromDate>
                     <eac-cpf:toDate standardDate="1959">1959</eac-cpf:toDate>
                  </eac-cpf:dateRange>
               </eac-cpf:useDates>
               <eac-cpf:alternativeForm>AACR2</eac-cpf:alternativeForm>
            </eac-cpf:nameEntry>
         </eac-cpf:identity>
      </egXML>
   </div>
</div>